Once, the residents of the demon
realm marched across the land,
Episode 2  Attack of the Xuán Guǐ Zōng!
seeking to scorch human the realm.
This was the War of Fading Dusk.
Humanity, at the brink of extinction,
sought the guidance of the
Xian immortals to give birth
to countless weapons for
their final counterattack.
These are the Shén Huì Mó Xiè.
Legendary treasures of supernatural
strength forged to let man
stand on even footing against demons.
With their incredible power,
the demons were forced back to
the depths of their own realm,
and peace returned to the world.
The few intact Shén Huì Mó Xiè
that had survived the war
were enshrined on holy ground
to ensure their incredible power would
not fall into hands of the wicked,
and watched over by the Hù Yìn Shī.
My clan, the Dān, are responsible for the
Duàn Jiàn Cí shrine where one is enshrined.
It is the sword named Tiān Xing Jiàn.
And even among the many Shén Huì Mó Xiè,
it is said to have extraordinarily
dangerous power.
But a group calling themselves
the Xuán Guǐ Zōng attacked,
hoping to pillage the mystic blade.
I see...  I have heard
that Miè Tiān Hái,
who leads the Xuán Guǐ Zōng,
is consumed by an unearthly fixation
on valuable and treasured swords.
But to think he'd be so brazen as to set his
sights on a legendary Shén Huì Xiè Mó?
Goodness gracious...
I apologize for not saying so
earlier, but my name is Dān Fěi.
Though I lack in strength, I am one of the
Hù Yìn Shī who guard the Duàn Jiàn Cí.
I don't know how to thank you both.
I am... just call me Guǐ Niǎo.
I'm a simple wanderer,
too insignificant to be called by name.
You were actually saved by
this fellow, Shāng Bù Huàn.
I didn't do it because I wanted to.
I was just caught up in your mess.
Still, after raiding its hiding place,
the Xuán Guǐ Zōng should
have what they were after.
Why chase you all the way out here?
No... the Tiān Xing Jiàn is still secure.
The pedestal it sits upon
has a seal placed upon it,
so that it can not be taken from the shrine.
Then the key to this seal...
The sword's handle and guard.
The Tiān Xing Jiàn's blade stands alone,
sealed within the Duàn Jiàn Cí.
Affixing its handle and guard and
restoring it to its original form
is the only way to remove
it from its pedestal.
Might I see that?
Yes, go ahead.
Since my predecessor passed the
duty of a Hù Yìn Shī onto me,
I have carried it with me at all times,
valuing it more than my life as I protect it.
My older brother was entrusted with
the handle in the same fashion.
But my brother... was killed
when Miè Tiān Hái arrived.
Now, then, Lady Dān Fěi...
What will you do next?
Avenge my brother, of course.
I will strike down Miè Tiān Hái.
I'll need to retrieve the Tiān
Xing Jiàn's handle as well.
You mean to tell me your big brother
was weaker than his sister?
No, not at all!
My brother was a first-rate swordsman.
I pale in comparison to him.
So how exactly are you gonna kill the man
who killed your brother,
if you're not even as good as him?
You might want to cool your
head and think it over.
That's...
But still, the Shén Huì Mó Xiè have
been targeted by foul villains.
I know there are those who will
come to my aid, if called upon.
But of course! And I, Guǐ Niǎo,
will gladly accompany you.
Thank you so much!
To ignore the call to duty
is to show cowardice,
wouldn't you say, most honorable hero,
Shāng Bù Huàn?
That's not funny. I flat-out refuse.
Come now, weren't you listening?
The ancient Shén Huì Mó
Xiè and their fearsome power
are on the verge into falling
into villainous hands.
None of my business.
I'm not a hero, a saint, or your servant.
And I make a point to avoid annoying trouble.
But you saved me before...
That was... the spur of the moment.
And a bit of goading, from him.
Like I said, I didn't do
it because I wanted to.
Still playing the selfish oaf...?
Well, let me make it clear, then!
I have no intention of getting involved any
further with a shrewd bastard like you!
You're calling yourself Guǐ Niǎo, right?
Maybe now you can risk your own
neck playing good Samaritan!
Got it?!
He's so upset...
Did I do something wrong?
You don't need to worry about it.
He's bound to be in a better
mood when you next see him.
I'll see him again?
You called, Master?
What has become of the Hù Yìn Shī girl?
We've no new information, sir.
We're trying to find the whereabouts
of this Shāng Bù Huàn
who Cán Xiōng informed us of.
Our men are stationed
along nearly every road.
It's a simple matter of
time until he is found.
Long ago I started my
collection priceless, mystic blades
whose names echo across the land,
but there are none that compare to
a work like the Tiān Xing Jiàn.
It is the very incarnation
of immortal secrets.
The notion of leaving it in a dusty Hù
Yìn Shī shack is out of the question.
You are a sword saint unrivaled
throughout the land, Master.
Only an incomparable masterpiece
is fit to hang at your side.
Spare me the flattery.
I desire only the key to unlock
the seal of the Duàn Jiàn Cí...
The sword guard the girl has.
Obtain it as quickly as possible!
Yes, sir. It will be yours.
If I obtain the Tiān Xing Jiàn's guard,
I wonder how much favor Lord
Tiān Hái will show me?
This should do.
What are those?
I've written letters calling
upon important allies,
since we will be challenging Miè Tiān Hái.
You have power over birds?
It will deliver the letters
to the nearest town.
And the bird master there
will then send them to their destinations,
along with different birds.
Are you always so well-prepared?
Dealing with people is a like
slipping through a hole in net.
Knowing the best methods for that
sort of thing is almost my only strength.
But Sir Guǐ Niǎo, why go so far to help me?
Due to certain circumstances, I am
acquainted with Miè Tiān Hái.
Eh?
You know him yourself?
Yes... and the Bones of Creation
is a dangerous man.
With the great power of the Shén Huì Mó Xiè,
he would surely bring ruin to the land.
Why didn't you appeal to Sir Shāng with
such a reasonable argument before he left?
Perhaps he might have agreed then.
Oh, he won't need convincing
to come to our aid.
But before, he said he
wouldn't help us anymore.
Even if we travel down different roads
right now, our destination is the same.
You're a very mysterious
person, Sir Guǐ Niǎo.
Good grief! Maybe now I can sleep on
something soft, with a roof over my head.
Right and—
What the...?
Hey, let me have one of your shaobing.
I'm closed for business
today! Try somewhere else!
Somewhere else...?
Look, I just want to buy some food.
I've even got money to pay.
You can take whatever you want, but please,
get out of here right now!
Before it's too late!
Hey!
What the hell's wrong with this town?
What is this?
"Any who trade with this man or speak to him
will be marked as a sworn enemy
of the Xuán Guǐ Zōng."
Guess I'm not sleeping indoors tonight.
Well, at least I got something to eat.
Are you Shāng Bù Huàn?
Who knows?
If I was him, I probably wouldn't want
to give my name to some damn stranger.
You make this Shāng fellow
sound like quite an eccentric.
Poor guy's been through Hell, I bet.
And now he's being real cautious about anyone
in this country who's on the side of the
road and making strange assumptions.
If you aren't Shāng Bù Huàn,
you can ignore this.
But the Xuán Guǐ Zōng are waiting
in ambush in the wilderness ahead.
It seems like this Shāng
guy's got really awful luck.
I've finally found you, Shāng Bù Huàn!
Are you the ones who posted
those weird warnings in town?
Well?!
Yes, that's right.
Did you like them?
Can't say it's much of a likeness.
Might ask you to redraw it with
me looking a bit more handsome.
Very well!
I'll make sure the picture on
your memorial is much nicer!
Just so you know, I cut ties
to the Hù Yìn Shī girl.
You can ask about where they are,
but I've got no answers.
Oh, really?
Well, that saves the trouble
of questioning you.
All that's left is to
avenge Cán Xiōng, then.
So that's how it's gonna be?
Listen, was this Cán Xiōng
your relative or your lover?
Don't make me laugh.
That fool is just the Xuán
Guǐ Zōng's disgrace,
who was beaten by some unknown vagrant.
If he were reborn, I'd return
him to the underworld myself!
You want to avenge someone
you barely care about?
Don't misunderstand me.
This is simply about saving face.
The Xuán Guǐ Zōng's soldiers
can not accept defeat.
If someone has defied us
and managed to survive...
That can't be ignored.
Is this the policy of
your leader, Miè Tiān Hái?
Yes, that's right.
The Master is a very proud man.
I could understand if he was risking
his own life for his pride.
But sending your servants to die
in vain isn't exactly praiseworthy.
You're still confused about who'll
die and who'll do the killing here?
How deliciously optimistic of you!
Yeah, that's right...
Not knowing how a fight to the death will
end is why people draw their swords.
I'd explain that to you,
but I doubt you'd listen!
Let me correct you, then.
You deserve death, and will die,
Shāng Bù Huàn!
Hold it right there!
Let those within earshot hear my words!
Let those who can see bear witness!
Arriving like a storm, shaking the earth...
The warrior whose name is
known throughout the East!
I am called the Frozen Wonder!
Juǎn Cán Yún and his spear have arrived!
Huh? Aren't we fighting?
Uh, yeah... What are you supposed to be?
Hey, now! That's kind of a rude
way to react to your savior!
Can't you spare some gratitude
or astonishment or something?
Look, it's pretty obvious, but we're
in the middle of something here.
If you don't wanna get hurt, back off.
Like I said, I'm here to take the fight
that's been picked with you off your hands!
What idiocy is this?!
Who are you, bastard?!
Like I said, I just told you!
I'm known as the Frozen Wonder, Juǎn Cán Yún!
You've probably heard of me, right?
I'm kind of a big deal lately.
I get it... you're one of those guys
who goes around thinking
whatever's convenient to him, right?
Have you ever listened to
someone in your entire life?
Shut up, you! I came here to save you,
so what's with the attitude?!
Why were you trying to save me, anyway?
Why? That's...
Wait, why are the Xuán Guǐ Zōng
after you, anyway?
It doesn't matter!
Get both of them!
Both of them, including the young one?
Whatever the circumstances,
the fool's standing against us.
If he wants to die that badly,
let's grant his wish.
Well, then...
What the—?! Where was that fired from?!
As there are those who see
nothing with both eyes,
there are those who can see
vast distances with one.
My gaze is the path of an arrow,
piercing those who fail to turn away.
When fighting someone in earnest...
There's but one thing to say.
Telling them you're going
to kill them is enough.
You talk too much, Juǎn.
Lady Liè Mèi, that came from
the other side of those woods!
Th-That can't be! No one could land
an arrow from that distance!
Aw man, there he goes.
I guess I'm not getting any action, now.
What the hell's going on?
I'd stay put if I were you, friend.
Move around too much, and you'll
get in the big man's way.
It's a messed-up thing
my bro Shòu tends to do.
He hates to stand out too much,
but he's an expert at stealing the spotlight.
Your bro?
You haven't met him?
But he said he was going on
before me to get a look at you.
Oh, the one-eye.
He had an odd bow, didn't he?
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
You saw my bro's one eye and steel bow,
and didn't recognize him as the
Sharp-Eyed Impaler, Shòu Yún Xiāo?
Do you live underwater or something?
Shut up! And leave me alone.
Damn you!
Meteor walking, eh?
I thought they were just weaklings, but...
Quite impressive.
You! Are you the Sharp-Eyed Impaler?
None other!
To see my arrows loosed and
face me without running...
If nothing else, you Xuán Guǐ Zōng
dogs are impressively bold.
Such nonsense!
No matter how skilled you are with that bow,
how can you fight us at this range?!
Even with your speed,
you'll only be able to hit two of us.
Then, the blade of the one left
standing will send your head flying!
Your famous name, known through the land,
comes to its end here...
Sharp-Eyed Impaler!
Well, now... we'll see.
Ridiculous! Have you gone mad?!
If you think people can
choose how they die...
You're gravely mistaken.
You dogs don't realize that your place
of dying has been chosen for you.
Nonsense!
Y-You...!
Wha—
For you to fall over from that blow...
I suppose I overestimated you.
I imagined you would've steadied
your footing with one less step.
What will you do?
Not many get a chance to choose
where they will die, you know.
Remember this! I will repay this dishonor!
What the hell was all that about?
I ask you again: are you Shāng Bù Huàn?
And what if I am?
Next Time  "The Woman In Night Devil Forest"
A voice whispers in the darkness.
A suspicious, enticing lullaby...
A woman's devilishness is
in full bloom at night.
Fall for the deception, and lose your life.