Episode 6  "Seven Comrades"
Must be nice, considering you
barely escaped with your life!
My life?
I don't recall it being in any
danger, much less escaping with it.
For me, lives are simply
something I take and destroy.
So you never even consider that
yours could be taken, huh?
You're a real positive thinker.
Would you stop getting on his case?
He's on our side now.
But he says he wants to
kill Mister Guǐ Niǎo!
And when the time comes,
you can sic your spear on him.
So just wait for now.
But if I beat him and
take the Soul Echo Flute,
it'd solve everything right here and now!
And if that happens...
You'll be famous as The Frozen
Wonder Who Kills His Comrades.
Man, what the hell?
He plays the flute and gets
to kill someone in exchange?
That's crazy, even for Mister Guǐ Niǎo!
Who accepts terms like that?
How wonderful that you care
so much for your comrades.
If you want to test your
luck with that spear,
I'll oblige you, whenever you want.
If you wanna blow that obnoxious flute,
then do it somewhere else!
You're a real pain in the ass!
How frightening.
Just what I'd expect from
a visitor from Xī Yōu.
Your threats carry genuine weight.
Did he say Xī Yōu?!
The rest of you should
mind your manners as well.
After all, he's apparently hardy enough
to cross the Wasteland of Spirits.
That's so stupid!
You crossed the Wasteland
of Spirits from Xī Yōu?
That's the craziest thing I ever heard!
It'd be more believable if you
said you flew down from the sky!
If you wanna bluff,
make it a little more plausible!
I'm not really worried about
whether you believe it or not.
Must be nice to be you!
Treating every damn thing
like it doesn't matter.
I guess you just wanna live out your
life like it's a half-hearted joke?
I'd think anyone who could live like
that would be better off for it.
Well, not me!
I'm not gonna end up some
nameless wanderer like you!
I'll beat the Screaming Phoenix
Killer one day and get famous!
And I'm not letting anyone stop me!
An ignorant kid talks down to
you like that and you just take it.
You're either quite the saint,
or an actual coward.
Either way's fine.
I'm just not young enough
to give a damn anymore.
But y'know, I'm surprised we're
suddenly hopping aboard a boat.
I'd guess Guǐ Niǎo arranged for it?
It'll be easier to keep out of the
Xuán Guǐ Zōng's sight this way.
It's a roundabout path to
the Demon Spine Mountains...
But it takes the same amount
of time as traveling over land.
But it's gotta cost a lot to buy
an entire boat out of the blue.
So what if it does?
Well, I mean...
Dān Fěi was practically chased
from the Duàn Jiàn Cí shrine,
so it's not like she had
time to gather funds.
Which means that our lodging during
the trip and the cost of this boat...
Guǐ Niǎo's been paying
for it all himself, right?
He must have.
And it's not just the money.
He's willing to risk his
life to see this through.
Come on, just who is this
Guǐ Niǎo guy, anyway?
Why are you asking me?
Because I get the feeling asking him
isn't gonna get me much of an answer.
And is your job here to find
out how I feel about him?
What do you mean "job"?
You can't blame me for being suspicious.
I don't know how you teamed up
with Guǐ Niǎo in the first place.
Whatever this is, it's not
me teaming up with him!
And yet the two of you managed
to convince Shā Wú Shēng,
and you're about to board
the same boat as him.
I'm telling you, it just
happened to turn out that way.
There are far too many questions about you.
Like where you came from
and what you're after.
None of that is clear.
Why do you even care about who I am?
It shouldn't matter to you, should it?
I had thought that was the case,
but if you're hiding something,
that changes things.
I wasn't hiding anything.
Then why this nonsense about
having come from Xī Yōu?!
Like I said, it's not nonsense.
It's inconceivable.
Do you realize how many heroes
have lost their lives
to the Wasteland of Spirits?
Taking a single step into that
chaotic, nightmare wilderness...
means having no hope of leaving it alive.
Come now, there's no
reason to interrogate the man.
A visitor from Xī Yōu? That doesn't
sound completely impossible.
Guǐ Niǎo...
How long have you been listening?
Around the part about nonsense.
I can't deny that it's
quite a lot to swallow...
This claim about Sir Shāng's origins.
But it's also true that it's the
only explanation that makes sense.
How's that?
Language, my friend.
Sir Shāng has an odd accent, but is
clearly fluent when speaking to us.
But it also seems true that he
hasn't been in the country long.
After all, he's never heard of the
Sharp-Eyed Impaler, the Night's Lament...
Or even the Screaming Phoenix Killer.
But it's hard to believe that he'd
be from a cloistered background,
like the Hù Yìn Shī.
The way he carries himself marks
him as a worldly individual.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, hang on!
I thought I just got lucky and you all
could speak the language of Xī Yōu.
We've been speaking the language of Dōng Li.
One that foreigners apparently find
quite difficult to learn.
That's right.
The point being that  Xī Yōu and Dōng Li,
prior to the War of Fading
Dusk, were one nation.
Xī Yōu
Wasteland of Spirits
Dōng Li
Demon Spine
Mountains
It was the sorcery of the demons that
created the Wasteland of Spirits,
splitting the nation down the middle,
which has led to 200 years of
separation between our peoples.
But it seems language has not
changed much in that time.
A foreigner speaking the same
language we use in Dōng Li...
It's logical to think he's from Xī Yōu.
But all of that...
It's meaningless speculation, if he's
only been pretending to be ignorant.
You don't think Sir Shāng can be trusted?
Exactly!
After all, he was already working with you.
Why's he so suspicious of everybody?
Well, as a man who made his
name in the arts of war...
That kind of caution may be
what helped him survive this long.
Hey, Guǐ Niǎo, just who...
Nah, never mind.
What do you want, human?
Well, you know...
I just wanted to ask you something.
Struck by a sudden interest in
the art of necromancy?
Uh, no, not that.
It's about Guǐ Niǎo.
You two seem to have
quite a history together.
I'm sure you realize exactly
how wretched a subject
that is to ask me about, right?
Do you want to enrage me that badly?
No, no!
I just wanna know about Guǐ Niǎo.
The more time passes, the less
I get what's going on with him.
Guǐ Niǎo?
You're a demon,
so I understand that you wouldn't
want the Tiān Xing Jiàn to be taken
from its resting place.
But why would he go through all
this trouble for the Hù Yìn Shī?
At first I thought he was just eccentric,
but he's willing to stake his
life on it. That's not normal.
Speaking as a demon,
the way you humans behave
is consistently illogical.
You babble about nonsense like
friendship, love, and justice,
and even risk your lives for them.
Uh... well...
Let's put aside the cultural
differences for a sec.
What do you, personally, think of Guǐ Niǎo?
That's what I was hoping to hear about.
Oh, I see.
You're trying to find out
where I stand. Is that it?
You needn't worry.
I resent it, but the fact remains
the where the Tiān Xing Jiàn is concerned,
his success is the best option I have.
There will be no treachery
until the matter is dealt with.
Old scores can be settled afterward.
Tell your master that.
Whoa, you seem to be getting the wrong idea.
Who do you think I'm working for?
Instead of trying these
petty schemes against me,
you should figure out what to do with the
Screaming Phoenix Killer, shouldn't you?
Maybe attack him as he
sleeps or poison him.
However it's done, you need to
retrieve the Soul Echo Flute.
Why's the conversation keep heading in
every direction except the one I want?
If you thought that I would
engage in idle gossip with you,
you've severely underestimated me.
I'm not exactly sure why you'd
be so suspicious of me.
Why wouldn't I be suspicious of some imbecile
who claims to have crossed the
Wasteland of Spirits from Xī Yōu?
Is there anybody Wú Shēng
didn't tell about that?
Compared to the other humans,
you're too much of an enigma.
You complain incessantly,
yet you're aboard the same boat as the
rest of us. What sense does that make?
If I'm going to stand
against Miè Tiān Hái,
we basically share the same objective.
If you wanted to end Xuán Guǐ
Zōng's enmity towards you,
you could've just killed
the Hù Yìn Shī girl
and presented them with the
Tiān Xing Jiàn's guard.
And that's what a demon would've done?
It's the logical thing to do.
But your motivation is the
furthest thing from reason.
You risk facing the Screaming
Phoenix Killer's blade.
Everything you say and do is illogical
and full of contradictions.
I'm just doing what I want to.
There's no reason to explain it to you.
In other words, you either have
some wildly devious scheme,
or are simply a moron who has lost his mind.
Either way, not someone I intend
on conversing with any longer.
Yeah, all right.
Sorry to trouble you.
Is something the matter? You're up so late.
What about you? Trouble sleeping?
Yes.
I've never been aboard
such a big boat before.
The excitement's made
it hard to settle down.
I haven't left the grounds of the
Duàn Jiàn Cí since I was a child.
And I thought that I would
simply live out my life
never knowing what the outside world held.
This journey has been full
of so many new things.
And, although I'm ashamed to admit it...
Doesn't matter what your duty is.
If you're enjoying yourself,
it's okay to admit it and smile.
They're two different things.
Right.
But the thing that's most wondrous
is how many people are
willing to help me in my duty.
I feel so grateful.
You say that, but...
There's no telling what any
of them are really thinking.
Is something bothering you?
Look...
What do you think about Guǐ Niǎo?
He's a wonderful man.
To be able to recruit a demon and
a lawless assassin to his cause...
He must be of truly remarkable character.
There's something about him that bothers me.
I can understand why you'd risk
your life for the Tiān Xing Jiàn.
But he's offering up his head
for the Soul Echo Flute...
And that makes me doubt his sanity.
Wouldn't that just mean
he intends to make amends with
Sir Wú Shēng during the journey?
I can't imagine how he could
make such a promise otherwise.
That never occurred to me!
I guess a sheltered young lady
has a different way of seeing the world.
Was what I said really that funny?
Nope. I'm genuinely impressed.
If everybody believed in the
goodness of people like that...
The world would be a lot easier to live in.
Do you not believe that
people are good, Sir Shāng?
Well, I want to, and there are
individuals that I do believe in.
But unfortunately, none
of them are on this boat.
What makes you think that?
I talked to them and saw firsthand.
Everybody thinks everybody
else is up to something.
At this rate, the trip's gonna be rough.
Everyone seems quite reliable to me.
We put our group together because
we'd be taking on a big group.
But I'm not sure, when it comes down to it,
if they're gonna be able to
work together, to be honest.
You truly are a kind person, Sir Shāng.
I mean, you seem to sincerely
care about our welfare.
I am truly glad, from the bottom of my heart,
that you decided to join us on this journey.
Dammit...
Stuff like this always makes
sheltered girls hard to deal with.
We're reaching the pier.
Once we leave the boat, we'll be within
a stone's throw of the Demon Spine Mountains.
Here's hoping we actually were
able to duck the Xuán Guǐ Zōng.
No...
Looks like we didn't get that lucky.
Just as our master predicted.
They came by the river after all.
I'm sure they thought
they had outwitted us.
What shallow plotting!
Two leading a force of enemies.
Simply killing them would be an easy matter,
but with this much cannon fodder,
reaching them could be a chore.
Wow, the infamous Screaming
Phoenix Killer's whining?
If someone was able to kill
the two of them before me,
they'd be known as the warrior
who outdid the Screaming Phoenix Killer.
You're serious? Not gonna take that back?
Certainly. I'll admit my defeat,
if you manage it.
Oh, yeah!
Move aside, all of you!
It's time for The Frozen Wonder of
the Spear to steal the spotlight!
Make way!
You're better at handling
the young than I'd imagined.
Maybe you should get a student of your own.
Nurturing people goes against my nature.
As soon as I see any potential in someone...
I start to want to kill them.
Hey, come on!
Are they gonna let him do this alone?
Isn't that too much?
Even if I wanted to help him,
without some fresh corpses...
My spells wouldn't be of much use.
There seems to be a sudden rise in the
corpse population, from what I can see.
In that case, would one of you go
and place these talismans on the corpses?
Listen...
Right. Consider it done.
Alternating Current Strike!
Damn!
This is getting a little harder!
What the?!
Now, dance, my precious puppets!
Necromancy?!
What in the world are they?!
Okay, this is a lot less heroic now!
All right, scary lady, why don't we
pick up where we left off the other day?!
Don't be conceited, you little fool!
You're about to get outperformed.
I suppose it's time, then.
I-Impossible!
The Screaming Phoenix Killer?!
Why are you here?!
If you want to show me up,
then you should at least
master Meteor Walking, boy.
Th-That's cheating, you bastard!
They're acting with one mind.
What wonderful coordination!
You gotta be kidding me...
Just a demonstration of their unity,
and the mutual trust between allies.
What do you think?
Do you still have any doubts about
my selections for this group?
None.
Now... who will die first?
If you can't decide,
I can make it simultaneous.
Fool, you can't falter now!
This is where we prove the true
strength of the Xuán Guǐ Zōng!
Withering Bone Melody!
Killer Strike: Prohibited Nocturne!
Oh, Master!
L-Liè Mèi!
Wh-What the?!
Master!
I suppose this could be
called a twist of fate.
Next Time  "Demon Spine Mountains"
The gates of Hell lie not only underground,
but can loom in the heavens as well.
The embodiment of all that
is evil in the world,
a place that is the lair
of most foul villainy.