Well, we've come across quite the obstacle.
Episode 5  "The Sword Devil, Shā Wú Shēng"
Our best chance of reaching the summit
of the Demon Spine Mountains
has fallen into the hands of the
most dangerous person imaginable.
But just who is this man?
I suppose a Hù Yìn Shī who has
spent her whole life on sacred ground
wouldn't know about someone so infamous.
He is Shā Wú Shēng,
a swordsman also known by his title
of the Screaming Phoenix Killer.
He makes his living as an assassin,
and is considered greatest
killer in the underworld.
And why's this guy hate you?
If you gathered together
everyone who hated this man,
you could hold a parade.
And I am included among
that number, of course.
Whoa, now, I thought you two had made up?
Our aligned interests take precedence now.
But unfortunately, not all consider the Tiān
Xing Jiàn to be as significant as I do.
I doubt we have anything we can use
to bargain with Shā Wú Shēng.
If this grudge is so intense,
would it be difficult to convince
him to hand the flute over after all?
Hey, come on, why's everyone
being so spineless about this?
This guy stole the Soul Echo Flute
from Mister Guǐ Niǎo's master, right?
That means we just take it back!
Why did you stop us, anyway?
Even if he is the Screaming Phoenix Killer,
I think this group attacking together
would have stood a fine chance.
Even though there was one
guy shaking in his boots!
There was a chance of victory,
but not a certain one.
More than that, our goal is
not to defeat Shā Wú Shēng.
We need to cross the Valley of the
Dead and the Valley of the Doll,
and to ensure that,
Xíng Hài and your master must reach
the Demon Spine Mountains in one piece.
We can't risk them being injured en route.
So as long as my bro Shòu
and the demon aren't hurt, it works out?
What are you getting at, Juǎn?
I hate to admit it,
but I don't have any big jobs to do on
our trek up the Demon Spine Mountains.
So if we just wager my
life to get the Soul Echo Flute,
there's no problem, right?
You intend to battle Shā Wú Shēng alone?
Wha—?!
Hey! Don't be stupid!
So what I'm stupid!
But this is a once-in-a-lifetime
chance for me.
If I'm the one to defeat the
Screaming Phoenix Killer,
my name will be heard throughout the land!
And if it doesn't work out
that way, you'll be dead, kid.
Dead?
I don't exactly have a
life to forsake, anyway.
To be out in the world with no reputation is
practically the same as not having been born.
Can't you see how you and I are both here?
Eating, talking, and being alive?
And maybe if I was as old as you,
I'd have given up, too.
But there's no way I'll be satisfied
with a life of just that.
But fighting alone seems... too reckless.
Hey, I can tell how good someone is
from having felt his sword firsthand!
Bottom line is, the guy's slowing down.
His reputation as #1 in the
underworld is old news, isn't it?
He might've scared me a bit at first glance,
but I've got him figured out now.
I can take him!
Hey, can't you talk some sense
into your stupid student?
When he gets like this,
there's no getting through to him.
It's a waste of time.
Some mentor you are.
What you're proposing is
essentially a gamble.
Personally, I'd rather handle this
matter with a more practical approach.
Let's wait until tomorrow morning
to confront Shā Wú Shēng.
I will spend the night seeing
if there's a preferable alternative.
If I come up with nothing,
I'll leave it to you.
Oh, I know!
There's a spell that turn the
blood of a corpse to acid,
then makes it burst forth.
Why not cast it on him while he still lives?
Then, once he's killed,
both he and his foe
will be melted into nothing!
How about we skip the suicide attacks?!
If Sir Guǐ Niǎo is unable
to come up with anything,
we will truly be out of options.
Should it come to that, I will
fight at Sir Juǎn's side.
H-Hey!
Seriously?!
For me?
What in the world do you mean?
The Soul Echo Flute is indispensable in
retrieving the Tiān Xing Jiàn's handle.
It's not only been stolen, but if there's
no other means to retrieve it...
I must be willing to accept
any fate to ensure its return.
Y-You're right!
I totally understand!
But I'm gonna take out that
Screaming Phoenix Killer bastard!
Dammit, I'm through listening to this!
Do whatever you want.
Man, what's with him?
He needs the Soul Echo Flute to make
it to Seven Sins Tower, too!
Sir Shāng has his own
way of handling things.
We can't expect him to act
according to our perspective.
Again, just to remind you,
do not act until tomorrow morning.
I want some time to consider this.
I'd like confronting Shā Wú Shēng
directly to be our last resort.
Yeah, yeah.
I can prepare a variety of
nightmarish spells as well.
Come and see me first thing in the morning.
I'm gonna respectfully decline, thanks!
I thought as much.
I knew you'd be the one to come.
One of my comrades intends to pick a
fight with you first thing tomorrow morning.
And he actually thinks he stands a chance.
How very gallant of him.
It's your fault for playing around.
You were taking it easy on him
at the temple, weren't you?
So he would underestimate you.
I'm afraid that I don't know
what you're talking about.
You made the whole situation
more complicated on purpose!
You wanna kill people that badly?
You'd ask me, of all people, that question?
Have you not heard that I am called
the Screaming Phoenix Killer?
Sure haven't. Apparently you're
a pretty big deal, though.
What's so funny?
Well, I can't help but feel a bit amused.
It's been a while since I've had anyone
else sit across from me at a table.
Do people consider you hard
to get along with, pal?
I suppose I've made too
much of a name of myself.
Usually...
This place would be full of
lively customers, even at this hour.
But when word gets out that the Screaming
Phoenix Killer is in the area,
this happens.
I'm surprised you didn't get thrown out.
The owner doesn't have the
nerve to complain to me.
I show some compassion by paying for
the time I've been here, at least.
If people hate you when
you're that considerate,
you must be known for
some real nasty business.
I'd think that if you'd heard
any of the tales about me,
you wouldn't have risked
talking to me like this.
Well, I'm a traveler, you know?
I haven't been in this country for long.
Where are you from, then?
Xī Yōu.
Xī Yōu...?
On the other side of the
Wasteland of Spirits?
Yeah, that's the one.
If you're joking,
it'd be funnier if you said
you swam upstream from the afterlife.
How could you have crossed
that accursed wilderness?
With the two legs I was born with.
Well, that has to be a joke.
No human could manage that.
Well, I'll admit,
it's a miracle that I made
it with both legs intact.
If what you say is true, it makes
sense that you wouldn't know my name.
I've never met someone from Xī Yōu, either.
Look, who cares about me?
I wanna talk about the Soul Echo
Flute that you've got right now.
Oh?
I don't know what happened
with you and Guǐ Niǎo,
but I'm asking you to find another
way to settle your vendetta with him.
Guǐ Niǎo...
So that's what he calls himself now?
How about it?
Devilwood
Flower
Garden
The man's ability to escape
me is almost god-like.
To ensure his death, I need something
that forces him to cross paths with me.
That brought me to this flute.
And I see no reason to give up
my trump card after finally acquiring it.
But that flute has a more important use.
Something that has nothing to do with you.
I have a more pressing question.
Did you really come here
thinking that you could
settle this with words?
I thought not.
Anyone who would have nodded at that...
Also would have lost their head long ago.
Don't be so scary, man.
Oh, but it's the truth...
If I'm being honest,
I've been thinking about nothing...
But killing you since you sat down.
I've been watching, intently,
for the perfect opportunity
to decapitate you in one stroke.
You're damned crazy.
You're one to talk...
No normal man would be on guard well enough
to avoid death at my hands this long.
You speak peacefully enough...
But are prepared for
any attack I could imagine.
You brazenly claim to want
to discuss the matter,
but you've been sitting there with a
mindset like a drawn blade all along.
I'm pleased to finally encounter
someone who knows what they're doing.
Maybe your claim of crossing the Wasteland
of Spirits isn't a lie after all.
You're saying that while we've been drinking,
we've already been fighting each other?
Only amateurs think battles
begin after swords are drawn.
Belief that bloodlust marks the beginning
in turn marks you as second-rate.
I haven't decided whether
I'm gonna fight you yet.
The path of the sword is
one of inevitability.
Your battle against those who
you will cut down begins the
moment you cross paths with them.
Only those aware of that
are truly first-rate.
And that's first rate? Sounds like those
guys are just going with the flow.
Trying to deny an inevitable fate is the
act of a fool who can not
see what their fate entails.
I'm not drawing my
sword unless I'm convinced...
that either you or I need to die.
Then you can leave right now.
And I will just kill the imbeciles
that call upon me in the morning.
An aversion to bloodshed...
That's a tendency your type always has.
And that makes this
conflict an inevitability.
You've known...
that you'd have to draw your blade
from the moment you laid eyes on me.
You just came here to give yourself
an excuse for when it happens.
Talk things over?
Don't lie to yourself with
such a hollow pretense.
Don't you ever have any doubts?
Or hesitate, for fear of making a mistake?
Never.
I have a simple method for clearing
away any doubts I may have.
The only thing that ever concerns me is
whether or not someone I've laid
eyes on is worthy of my blade.
And the moment after I raise that question,
I find a corpse at my feet.
And so, in the 15 years since
I've mastered the sword,
I have never been troubled by doubt.
You drew it...
Yeah.
Who should live? The idiot who's
trying his hardest in life,
or the bastard who could live
or die with little difference?
That question helped me make up my mind.
Such mental detours
will only dull your blade...
If you want to win, you need to deal
with fate in more concise terms.
I don't give a damn about fate.
I choose when to draw it and when to strike.
That's my sword!
One last question: have you ever
heard the title "Enigmatic Gale"?
I haven't.
Like I said, I'm not up to date on
local affairs here in Dōng Li.
I thought as much...
How sad. To dance to
his tune with no idea...
What are you talking about?
Don't worry about it.
Besides, if you die here,
you'll have no cause to regret it.
Good grief. Do the two of you have some
sort of grudge against chairs and tables?
Hallucinogenic smoke... Damn you again!
Guǐ Niǎo! Did you pull some
kind of weird trick again?!
What are you doing?!
I'm sorry. Weren't you the one talking
about how he'd rather avoid
a fight to the death?
Uh... W-Well...
And you, Wú Shēng.
I thought you were after me?
Don't go changing targets for no reason.
No matter what kind of illusions
you use, you won't fool me again.
I have no intention of
letting this flute go!
And I will cut down anyone who approaches me!
So now what?
Think you can still escape me?
No, you can have the Soul Echo Flute.
It belonged to my master,
so take good care of it.
Now that I think about it,
no matter who holds it,
there's no problem as long as they guide
us through the Labyrinth of Darkness.
And luckily enough, you have some
skill at playing it. What do you say?
Care to join us on the trip
to the Demon Spine Mountains?
Are you absolutely insane?
If we make it through the Labyrinth of
Darkness safely, I'll offer you my head.
That's quite the bold offer.
Does this matter involving the Tiān Xing
Jiàn really hold so much value to you?
I always make sure to complete any
task I start. It's that simple.
So be it.
You've piqued my interest.
It might be interesting to visit the castle
that belongs to the
infamous Bones of Creation.
Then prepare for a journey.
We meet at the dock tomorrow at noon.
Hey!
What in the hell?
Make your peace with your
head during the journey.
Because when we reach the summit,
I will be taking it from you.
What are you gonna do
about making a promise like that?
I'll ponder that one as we go along.
I have until we exit the Labyrinth
of Darkness to figure out
if I really do need to
present my head to him.
I might come across some
inspiration in the meantime.
You make it sound so damn easy.
In contrast, the matter of the Soul
Echo Flute had to be solved tonight.
Rather... I had to take action
the second you made your move.
So, with my hand forced,
this was the option I was left with.
Desperate times and all that.
So should I have minded my own business?
Oh, not at all.
I befriended you because I knew
you were that type of man.
I'm not your damn friend!
How many times do I need to say it?!
I'd say you have bigger concerns
than worrying about me,
because it seems that Wú Shēng has
taken quite an interest in you.
He might try and kill you once
he's taken my head, you know.
I'll think about that
as we go along, I guess.
I imagine Juǎn will be quite disappointed.
He seemed to be looking forward
to the duel of his lifetime.
Gotta ask, why'd you stop us back there?
On the off chance I had won that duel,
you would've gotten the Soul Echo Flute
without having to make that crazy deal.
You could've just waited
to see how it played out.
As I said before, I'd rather keep the group
together until we reach Seven Sins Tower.
Shòu Yún Xiāo's bow, Xíng Hài's song,
and the Soul Echo Flute...
You've got everything you need, don't you?
I'm not part of the equation.
Hardly. You have a task
that only you can complete.
One important enough to make
me offer my head as collateral.
What the hell's that?
I'm not telling yet!
Although, if you swear to do it,
I'd be willing to explain...
In other words, you're still
dead-set on using me somehow?
Think of it as the two of
us helping each other out.
It's a bumpy road up
the Demon Spine Mountains...
You summoned me, Master?
Have you found the the
Hù Yìn Shī girl yet?
I'm sorry, sir.
I've dedicated more men to the search, but...
No.
It may be a waste of time
trying to search for them.
Sir?
Just as they have the Tiān Xing
Jiàn's guard, I have its handle.
If we both wish to complete it,
then won't they be coming to us?
To Seven Sins Tower?!
I can't imagine it.
Are they truly that foolish?
Is it foolish? Or could they be far
more capable than we've anticipated?
Either way, I'm looking forward to it.
Just what kind of plot...
will the Enigmatic Gale hatch?
Next Time  "Seven Comrades"
Scheming beneath a smile...
A poison needle, hidden within a handshake.
Only those who are able to expect the
unexpected will survive to see tomorrow.