Not long... Not long now at all!
Until the hammer of judgment will
fall on the world of the humans!
Final Episode: "A New Duty"
What is that supposed to be?
What kind of ridiculous prank is this?
I have slain the Screaming Phoenix Killer,
from whom you constantly fled.
And you dare challenge me with a sword?
Perhaps instead of making
your name as a thief,
you should have become a clown!
Is it really that strange?
Enough!
I have no intention of standing
on the same stage as a jester.
If you desire an opponent so badly,
a beast is more than worthy enough
a foe to keep you amused!
I will have the demon
bird I summon attack you.
Let's see if your alleged
sword skill can protect you
before it leaves only your bones behind!
No need to rush. Here is your opponent...
Those whistles let you command
the demon bird you summon.
But how will a demon bird called
by a broken whistle react?
What?
Driven into a frenzy, it will attack
the one who used the whistle.
Am I right?
Bastard... then your attack was for this?
Well done! As expected from
the Bones of Creation.
To demonstrate such power by
simply channeling your battle qi!
For you to be this skilled...
It should have been a simple matter
to settle things with Shā Wú Shēng.
Why did you run and hide like a coward?
That man desired an opponent
stronger than himself, yes?
I don't see how I'm obliged to indulge
someone who wants to kill me.
And instead you endured humiliation?
No... for someone with skill like yours,
why do you shame yourself as a thief?!
Well, I'd grown bored with the sword.
Bored?!
Yes.
The path of the sword is one where
mastery unveils certain truths.
When I was younger, I thought
that would suffice...
But one day, I had a realization.
It is lies and deception that
reign supreme in my soul.
You varlet!
Very well...
What kind of swordplay could
give birth to such a heresy?
It's time that I saw for myself!
How's that?
Speed is the foundation of sword techniques!
Can you match my blade's velocity
with your half-hearted discipline?!
Matching blow for blow is exhausting...
Why don't we just say that
we're even, in this case?
But what about the power of your strikes?
Try not to break that precious sword
of yours by swinging it too hard, now.
We need it to seal Yāo Tú Lí, after all.
Unacceptable!
I refuse to accept this!
For a fool like you...
To dare to stand against my sword!
If you believe that dedication
and passion alone will give birth
to equivalent results...
Then you're living in a naive dream.
Does it frustrate you? Do you find it unfair?
I'd say that those values you hold dear
are exactly what prevent you from
grasping the true nature of combat.
Silence!
The fact that you sought to become
a peerless warrior alone proves
you don't understand a thing.
The path you walk does not lead
to the summit of a mountain,
but something like a bottomless ocean.
The greater your mastery, the more
apparent the infinite depths become.
You, who scorn and make
light of the sword...
Don't talk as if you understand it!
If anything, I got tired of it
because I didn't make light of it.
With my next blow, I will end this!
Finally taking things seriously, then?
Well, let's move onto the climax.
Demonic War Force: Hellborn Rebellion!
White Heavens: Lunar Crater Vapor!
Why did you put your blade away?
My skills gave birth to
a foul sword for killing.
Continuing down that path in
earnest would lead to villainy.
And I found that notion boring.
I don't believe in removing
evil from this world.
It's far more fulfilling to make a
mockery of the villains who embody it.
A battle like this...
it was all to humiliate me?!
You were the most exquisite
prey I've had in a while.
I see. You really have defeated me.
That being the case, I will take something
of even greater value from you!
The humans that bring you such amusement...
This world that you derive such joy from...
Good or evil, all of it will be destroyed!
You... You can't mean to...
You're going to break the sword?!
Why would you do that?!
Now, no one can stop Yāo Tú Lí...
I've simply done as you did, Enigmatic Gale.
It seems I, too, desire to see
despair on someone's face!
What now, Lǐn Xuě Yā?
Because of your thirst for mischief,
you've doomed the world.
How does it... feel?
To die while laughing, after facing me....
The arrogance of it.
After crushing your prideful soul...
You still...
How dare you!
How dare you, you coward!
You were defeated! You should
have submitted yourself to shame!
You should've shed tears of regret!
Why else were you born?!
Why did you fight me?!
After all the trouble you've caused me,
you run away with my prize?!
Damn you! Damn you!
Calm down. There's nothing
to be gained from anger.
Let's turn to more appealing
pursuits. For instance...
Consider yourself honored, my kin.
The time has come to shake the
sun-bathed lands with my roar once more.
This beatific sensation! This joy!
The dream of demonkind will
at long last be reality!
What the hell's that?!
The demon god Yāo Tú Lí!
That's impossible!
I was worried about this.
If it was defeated, but not sent back home...
There's nothing else that could've
been done besides penning it up.
For an abomination to have
been beneath our feet...
We had no idea,
despite living on the holy grounds.
Don't blame your ancestors.
There are some times when your only
option is to keep something quiet.
Oh, it's all of you.
What brings you to the middle of this mess?
Enigmatic Gale!
I figured you would've been ahead of us.
What of the Tiān Xing Jiàn?
Miè Tiān Hái destroyed it.
And now we have no means
to stop that demon god.
Oh... Oh no.
What do you mean, he destroyed the sword?!
You bastard! You probably backed
him into a corner, didn't you?!
How the hell are you gonna
make up for this, huh?!
If it falls to me to make amends...
Then we need another Shén Huì Mó
Xiè in the Tiān Xing Jiàn's place.
That means finding the nearest shrine,
and stealing it from the Hù Yìn Shī.
That's no different than
what Miè Tiān Hái did!
It'd be quite the tragedy if another demon
god was underneath that shrine, too.
Is this really the time to be making jokes?!
A demon god just woke up!
It's the end of the damn world!
Hey, slow down a bit.
We haven't even tried anything.
Until you run out of options, you're better
off feeling like you can crack jokes.
I feel as if that's the first
nice thing you've said about me.
Man, shut the hell up.
Sir Shāng, where are you going?
Until we run out of options,
it's worth trying the ones we do have.
After all, it's the end
of the world otherwise.
Is it all right if we keep
our distance and watch?
Sounds good to me.
Sir Shāng?
Wait.
Does that look like someone
who's going off to die?
But he's facing a demon god!
With the Tiān Xing Jiàn gone,
what could he do?
I'm sure that means he has something in mind.
The Tiān Xing Jiàn... Tiān Xing Jiàn!
The accursed Tiān Xing Jiàn!
The pathetic needle that kept
me entombed in that hole!
But I no longer need concern
myself with its existence.
There is nothing to stand in my way!
And now, I will burn! And I will destroy!
You seem excited, almighty demon god.
But I can't imagine you're
fully awake just yet!
Bow down, pitiful rodent.
The only hope of your kind,
the Tiān Xing Jiàn sword, is lost!
Swords, swords, swords!
Someone opens their mouth,
and it's usually to yap about swords!
Would you all give it a rest?
Swords are nothing more than tools.
No different than a toothpick
you use to clean your teeth!
Whether it cuts something or protects
someone just depends on who uses it!
You creatures, with lives
shorter than an insect's...
What could you hope to accomplish
with your feeble limbs?
Well, let's see.
With two arms and ten fingers,
we can make use of tools.
And the good thing about tools...
is that you can always get a replacement!
They've bewitched people and
brought chaos to the land!
Demonic swords, spectral swords,
holy swords, unholy swords...
The 36 pieces I gathered
while traveling Xī Yōu...
I've got everything from devil
banishers to god killers!
Which edge do you want a taste of?!
You can't be killed...
But you've got no intention of going home.
I figure a troublemaker like you
would be best matched with this!
The Absolute Phantom: Jié Huāng Jiàn!
You! What manner of creature are you?!
Like I said, I'm just a human being.
A human who just happens to have a
variety of tools at his disposal.
Take this!
Now, time for the biggest job since
your creation, Jié Huāng Jiàn!
Come forth, Forbidden Prison
of Absolute Desolation!
Wh-What is this?!
It isn't the demon realm.
What is this darkness?!
To the ends of the stars... You'll be
lost on the edge of space for eternity!
See ya!
Curse you!
Curse you—!
That oughta do it.
Hey, I'm all done.
Wh-What was that?
What's become of Yāo Tú Lí?
Well, let's just say I sent her somewhere
she'll never find her way back from.
A sword that would inspire
fear in a demon god...
And you've got 36 of them?!
There are idiots like Miè
Tiān Hái in every country.
And because you have wizards and sages
who keep making the stupid things,
there's always some around to cause trouble.
I'd been gathering them up
to get rid of them,
but eventually a group started plotting
against me with an eye toward stealing them.
Which is why you left Xī Yōu
and ended up here, in Dōng Li?
I was looking for a place where
I could dump 'em all safely.
But before I knew it, I'd crossed
the Wasteland of Spirits
and was in the next country over.
Though I'm at least glad I managed to lose
the bastards who were after my inventory.
That being said, that's one taken care of...
And I'm glad to be rid of it.
I wasn't sure what to do with
that one in particular.
You're giving it... to me?
It takes about a hundred years for the
hole in space to completely close up.
In the meantime, the sword
needs to stay where it stands.
A new job for the Hù Yìn Shī who guard
these holy grounds, in other words.
Right!
You're going to rebuild the holy
grounds to keep another sword safe?
Good grief... an exhausting notion.
You guys can do it though, right?
Yeah, leave it to us.
Right?
Yes.
Faster and more accurately!
You're still looking far too shabby!
C-Can we take a little break?
My arm's killing me...
This is just sad!
How can you be giving up already?
Now that you're part of the Dān clan,
you have a duty to master all
the Dān Blade Techniques!
I kinda think a spear still suits me better.
Honestly! Are you going to whine
like that in front of your son, too?
You're a man! You must shape up!
Now, again, from the beginning.
Right...
You two take care.
Leaving without saying a word?
Such a rush!
I'm sure they'd love the
opportunity to say goodbye.
Look, I hate that kind of stuff, all right?
We're all still alive. We might meet again.
I have to say, I'm sad to see
someone so interesting go.
You better not try following me, you bastard!
Or what? You gonna steal
something from me next?
Relax.
You don't have anything
I would want to steal.
Here, a parting gift.
From the look of the sky, there's
bound to be some rain this evening.
I can't imagine you want to start your
journey running around like a wet rat.
Well... you really put
me through the wringer,
so I guess I can accept
an umbrella as payment.
I have to say, that makes
it quite the bargain.
See ya.
It's true he has nothing for me to steal.
But if he's carrying around that
dangerous collection of mystical weapons...
All manner of villains will
continue to set their sights on him.
And among them, there may be
those able to pique my interest.
There's no way I'm missing
an opportunity like that.
Man, forget "some rain."
This looks like a real storm.
No way is a single umbrella gonna cut it.
Even a storm that could ruin an umbrella
is not enough to halt a man's journey.
Tread through wind and rain, and you're
bound to encounter a muddy stream.
And if it must be crossed,
it is best to do so unclad.
Sequel Now In Production
For More Information, Visit the Official Site
Official Site