Episode 11: "A Proud Life"
What is this?
That's rather modest attire, for you.
Hey, your people are the
ones who gave it to me.
Er, I mean, rather... I happened
to tear my usual clothes, you see.
Not to mention it's rather out of character
for you to be carrying a sword around.
What's gotten into you?
Come on, what's it matter?
There are times when even someone like
me feels more comfortable bearing arms.
The Hù Yìn Shī's blade would've
struck me as far more appealing.
What could have caused you to choose
that shabby looking piece of scrap?
Well, excuse me for having a shabby sword!
Er, I mean... this one has
its own unique appeal.
You are an odd one.
No matter.
Here, this is for your demon bird.
Do you know how to use it?
Yeah, more or less...
There we go!
I can't help but wonder
how you learned that.
You truly are a puzzle.
Yeah, I gotta admit...
I'm with you there.
What's the matter? Afraid of heights?
A rather sad state for the
Enigmatic Gale to be in.
Man, shut up!
Er, I mean, I could use some distraction.
What could we discuss?
You want idle chat, at a time like this?
What could you and I possibly
have to discuss at this point?
Well, let's see...
There's been something
I've been curious about.
According to you, the Tiān Xing Jiàn
is the ultimate sacred sword, right?
And what of it?
I mean, there are plenty of other famous
weapons among the Shén Huì Mó Xiè...
How can you be so sure the Tiān
Xing Jiàn is the greatest?
A bit of research into the
truth of the War of Fading Dusk
makes the Tiān Xing Jiàn's
remarkable nature obvious.
That the Shén Huì Mó Xiè are weapons
that could slay the gods of the demons...
is a misconception held by society.
No matter how divine the
honing of a weapon may be,
it is not enough to permanently
slay a demon god.
The best one could manage is to
use one to exhaust the creatures
to the point of contrition.
In other words, the Shén Huì
Mó Xiè do not slay demons,
but were weapons used to force
them to return to their own realm.
Yeah, you hear rumors about the
demons building up their forces
in the demon realm occasionally.
With my expertise in dark sorcery,
I am capable of communicating
with the demon realm.
The demon gods who led the invasion
into the human realm 200 years ago
are all still active there,
with one major exception.
There's one exception?
Yes. That is Yāo Tú Lí.
And after the War of Fading Dusk,
he was the only one who failed
to return to the demon realm.
In the records of the human realm,
it is told that a demon god bearing the
same name did battle against
the Tiān Xing Jiàn.
Then that would mean...
Exactly. The other Shén Huì Mó Xiè
only managed to force their foes back...
While the Tiān Xing Jiàn was the
only weapon on the battlefield
to actually strike down one of
leaders of the demonic forces.
Thus, that sword
is truly the greatest of the
myriad Shén Huì Mó Xiè.
That is the conclusion I came to.
You really think so?
You doubt my view of the situation?
I mean, we're talking about
creatures that don't operate
on the same logic as this world does.
You can't even say for sure if they have
a "life," as we understand the concept.
Could someone really kill something like
that, in the true sense of the word?
A mere thief...
And you claim some greater knowledge
of the demon realm's inhabitants?
Or are you claiming you've seen
one yourself in the past?
Oh, no, no, of course not.
Last night, there were
visitors other than myself.
There are three cups...
Two in addition to Miè Tiān Hái.
Now, then...
The most likely conclusion, given that
Shā Wú Shēng fought his way here,
is that Shòu Yún Xiāo and Xíng
Hài, along with Juǎn Cán Yún,
made it through the Labyrinth of Darkness...
And are here at Seven Sins Tower.
That means I need to complete this
job even faster than I had thought.
Now, then... a keyhole is always a bit
more delicate and temperamental
than even the finest lady...
Which makes the effort all the
more worthwhile, in the end.
The payment you asked for is going
to be delivered to this location.
Yeah, for shady deals like this,
I can see why you'd want
to avoid prying eyes.
Here it comes, sir.
We've gathered the five thousand jīn of
gold from local areas, as you commanded.
This is the cart with it all.
Well done.
Now, if you'd just confirm the contents...
Right, then.
Indeed. As I'd expect
of the Bones of Creation,
you hold up your end of the
bargain without much fuss.
Now, I suppose it's my turn.
As for the Tiān Xing Jiàn's guard...
Let's see... was it to the
east or west of this place?
If you are the Enigmatic Gale...
You should be able to tell the
weight of the the contents
from the cart's movements alone.
Now, tell us the weight of the cart!
I mean... it's gotta be however much five
thousand jīn of gold weighs, right?
Fool!
The only crate that contained
any gold was the one at the top!
Why the hell would you try
to trick me after all this?!
I never intended to make
this an honorable exchange.
But seeing what kind of deal the
great Lǐn Xuě Yā would offer...
I was quite interested to
see how it would play out,
so I indulged your little farce.
But to be quite honest, I'm disappointed.
The disguise was quite remarkable,
but your acting was atrocious.
Just who are you? And where
is the real Lǐn Xuě Yā?
Just toying with me, huh?
Well, if you were willing
to play along until now,
that works perfectly for me!
Don't let him escape!
Fill him with regret for underestimating
the Xuán Guǐ Zōng!
Damn! This goes way beyond
being the crappier job!
I should've never gone along
with that bastard's plan!
Shall we capture him alive, and question
him about Lǐn Xuě Yā's whereabouts, sir?
No. I'm assuming his function...
is to act as bait to lure me
away from Seven Sins Tower.
Which makes the Enigmatic
Gale's real whereabouts
obvious beyond the point of consideration.
Then...
Kill him!
Xuán Guǐ Zōng, demonstrate why
I have chosen you as my hounds!
Yes, sir!
Did he imagine that in my desire for
the Tiān Xing Jiàn's guard,
I would grow oblivious to the truth?
How unfortunate for you, Enigmatic Gale.
But I've been one step ahead of you.
If the Tiān Xing Jiàn's
handle isn't in here...
Then did that wretch Miè
Tiān Hái take it with him?
Could he intend to head
to the Duàn Jiàn Cí  as soon as
he has the guard to break the seal?
No... that's unlikely.
He was already wary of me
while we were negotiating.
Rather than expecting to receive the guard,
he would've been prepared for the
likelihood I had some trap ready.
He'd know there would be a risk in
walking about with his precious handle.
The careful thing would be
to keep the handle in this safe
until the guard was also in his hands.
No... wait a moment.
If, unrelated to our deal, he had been given
an alternative path to obtaining the guard...
Wait! I can sense a Spirit
Vein in the area.
Spirit Vein?
It's something like a wide river through
which the power of the land flows.
If it's affected the land enough,
then we should be able to interact with it.
Do you see anything that looks like
a Spirit Tree in the vicinity?
Let's see...
Hey, could that be it?
I'm sure of it!
We're in such good luck!
It seems the heavens haven't forsaken us yet.
But what good's it gonna do?
Come, take my hand.
I call upon the high heavens to
grant us the form of lightning.
Hidden from the stars,
where will the path of dragons
deep within these woods lead us?
A-Amazing! We got here in a flash!
It's always been tradition for temples
to be built near Spirit Veins.
What a relief...
If Sir Shāng is right, and the Tiān
Xing Jiàn's guard is hidden here,
we'll be obtaining it before anyone else.
Y-Yeah!
Found something! Is this it?!
Yes, I'm sure of it!
This time, it's the real one.
Well, that's good to hear.
You!
If you had followed my teachings, and
minded what was going on behind you....
You would've noticed us trailing
you at least three times.
Any student of mine would've
noticed five times.
And it's not just the Hù Yìn Shī
who can control the Spirit Veins.
Just how careless could you people be?
Oh, no...
But... why'd you follow us?!
I thought you two were after the
handle at Seven Sins Tower!
It was a simple deduction.
Knowing the girl's personality,
she'd prioritize retrieving
the Tiān Xing Jiàn's guard.
If she left the Demon Spine Mountains
the moment she was freed,
it'd mean the guard that the Bones
of Creation has is a forgery.
And that you two were headed to the
hiding spot of the genuine article.
So, after discussing it with Miè Tiān Hái,
we used demon birds to follow you
after you left the mountain.
And surely enough...
I would never have guessed
it was hidden in this place!
You sided with the Xuán Guǐ
Zōng like it was nothing?!
Do you really want the Tiān
Xing Jiàn that badly?!
Of course.
Especially since we have a
buyer who sees it as priceless.
How could we not seek to steal it?
You'd make no distinction
between friend or foe.
How despicable!
You can't have it!
You're not my brother or anything else now!
Listen to the little pup howl!
Expect no mercy with your true
nature exposed, necromancer!
As far as Hù Yìn Shī are concerned,
sharing a boat ride is far less appealing...
Than engaging in a battle to the death!
Miss Dān Fěi!
I told you not to let your
emotions get the better of you.
Are you trying to waste
everything I taught you?
Open your eyes, Cán Yún.
Your doubts are only due to youth.
If it's just this one time,
I won't hold it against you.
Now... be a good lad and hand the guard over.
I refuse!
Cán Yún!
True pride is something
you trade your life for!
When you said that, it really
struck a chord with me!
Then why fight?!
You made it clear to me!
In order to die a proud death some day,
I can't live in a way I'd be ashamed of!
Such nonsense!
Even if I am laughed at for
falling with nothing to my name,
I choose to live life in
accordance with my principles.
Rather than living out
my days accruing glory,
I seek to die with a
satisfied smile on my face.
Celestial Thundershock!
Reflections of Death!
You damned—
Little fool!
Well done, Yún Xiāo!
Sir Juǎn!
How ridiculous...
Have you forgotten what your duty is?
I won't let anyone else die!
That naivete will cost you.
Dān Blade Technique: Scorching Rainbow!
Damn them!
Don't bother.
We have what we came for.
There's no reason to bother
with those peons any further.
Well, I suppose you're right.
Now we just need to take this guard
and meet with Miè Tiān Hái.
We don't have time to waste on detours.
Right.
But I have to say, that was
simpler than I had imagined.
And the smaller the group,
the larger the stake we each get.
I'm so sorry, Miss Dān Fěi.
Because I got in the way,
you lost that important guard...
It's all right.
Instead of losing our lives,
let us swear to face them again
with unwavering determination.
I realize now how that is true courage.
You taught me that, Sir Juǎn.
Aw, no...
After your wound has healed,
let us face Miè Tiān Hái.
And this time, we will
take the Tiān Xing Jiàn.
The lock's been broken from the outside.
Then someone rescued Lady Dān Fěi.
While two others accepted an
invitation from Miè Tiān Hái...
That makes the situation fairly clear.
If our Hù Yìn Shī has
quietly left the mountain...
That blasted Shāng Bù Huàn.
He must've told her the
location of the real guard.
Good grief...
It's always so difficult to work with
people who are motivated by emotion.
I may as well assume the guard has fallen
into the Bones of Creation's clutches.
In that case, he's got only one destination.
I'll circle around, set
a trap, and perhaps...
Luck will smile upon me once more.
Next Time  "A Blade That Doesn't Cut"
Undeterred by the pain of his wounds,
the man laughs in the face of mockery.
Who was it who called upon this vagabond,
this man who came from the distant west?