Episode 12: "A Blade That Doesn't Cut"
This is strange. I know he ran this way!
Forget about this place. Let's head
back and take another look around.
Man, talk about a persistent bunch.
Well, I guess I can relax a bit for now.
Have to say, abandoning the deal
at the most critical moment...
What the hell is Miè thinking?
I thought he wanted the
Tiān Xing Jiàn's guard.
Wait, hang on...
Did he have another line on getting the
guard, and that made him drop the deal?
That'd be bad news.
I better go check out Limitless Temple.
Sir Shāng! You're all right!
I thought you were at Seven Sins Tower?
And what are you two doing here?
And Juǎn Cán, what happened to your eye!?
Sir Juǎn has parted ways with
Shòu Yún Xiāo and Xíng Hài,
and rescued me.
But the two of them followed
us to Limitless Temple.
And I screwed up.
I didn't realize they were following us...
And ended up leading them straight
to Miss Dān Fěi's treasure.
I guess things have gotten even more
complicated without me knowing.
So, Yún Xiāo and Xíng Hài have
the Tiān Xing Jiàn's guard?
They intend to sell it to Miè Tiān Hái.
Now it's only a matter of time
until the Duàn Jiàn Cí's seal is broken.
Lǐn was supposed to swipe the handle
from a safe at Seven Sins Tower.
But considering this news,
that seems unlikely.
Miè Tiān Hái may have predicted
every bit of what we were up to.
If only I had done as you said,
and waited inside of the cage,
this wouldn't have happened.
Well, if that bastard
Lǐn's plan got messed up,
then I guess it works out fine.
Even if they target villains,
someone who gets their kicks from making
a mockery of people still makes me sick.
We'll just have to take the Tiān
Xing Jiàn back the noble way.
How the hell is it fine?!
Fixing this mess is about
more than your whims!
Miss Dān Fěi is desperate, all right?!
And I was fighting for my life with a
man who I used to treat like a brother!
And here you are, in high
spirits! What's so damn funny?!
But Sir Juǎn, I believe he's
just trying to encourage us.
I never asked for encouragement!
This is the last guy
I want to get a lecture from!
What exactly is it about me
that gets on your nerves?
Because I have absolutely no idea
what's going on in your head!
You're always laughing at and
being shocked by the wrong things!
You don't care about honor or fame,
but you always stick your
nose in when there's trouble!
Are you being sincere?
Or are you screwing around?
Things being how they are,
I can't help but feel
like you're mocking me!
But...
Look, I didn't mean anything by it.
I mean, who are you even supposed to be?
You openly wear a sword,
and have the air of a real master.
But you don't act like a big deal!
You never even gave us your title!
What is it you want?!
Come on, those titles aren't something
you come up with yourself.
It's something others start
calling you on their own.
Then I'll come up with one for you!
Let's see... you're trying to show off with
that sword that can barely cut anything,
so how about "The Edgeless Blade"?
Oh, no!
So a sword that doesn't cut, huh?
That's right! The Screaming
Phoenix Killer told us.
The only impressive part about your
fighting is how you channel power.
Compared to that, your swordplay has
no edge at all and is all show.
I get it. Hence, the Edgeless Blade?
Nice. Suits me fine.
I'll take it.
Seriously, what is your deal, man?!
We have you now, you lousy actor!
Did you honestly think you could escape?!
The Xuán Guǐ Zōng!
So damn persistent... you
guys still haven't given up?
You gave us some trouble, but we
caught additional prey thanks to you!
A perfect example of two
birds with one stone!
I'll hold them off.
Miss Hù Yìn Shī, take our
wounded friend and get out of here.
No! You can't mean to face them alone.
Take them!
Go! Get out of here, Dān Fěi!
But...
You fool.
You think we'd let them escape?!
Bastard! Bring it on, then!
I don't think so!
Your idiocy knows no end! To throw
away your weapon like that...
Huh... what'd I throw away, now?
Oh, no!
I need to get this to him!
Wh-What is this thing!?
Sir Juǎn?
This sword... it doesn't
have an cutting edge.
No, it's not even iron!
He just took a piece of
wood and painted it silver!
That can't be...
Then how does he...?
You bastard! How did you
do that without a sword?!
You need to stop making dumb assumptions.
See, I was never using a
sword in the first place.
Impossible!
This can't be!
Did you think that only sharpened
metal could form an edge?!
Don't presume so much, boy!
If you channel the right force into it,
then hair and cloth can split flesh
and shatter bone!
Just who in the world are you?!
They call me the Edgeless
Blade... apparently.
Though, we just came up with that.
Amazing...
Now, then... if you run, I won't chase you.
Damn you!
Do not underestimate the
Xuán Guǐ Zōng's fortitude!
Festering... Bone Heart!
Formless Rogue Sword: Specter Shattering!
You damn fool...
It never occurred to you to run, train
hard, and take another shot at me?
You... you've been fighting
with this sword all along?
Pretty good, right?
Doesn't rust when it's wet, easy to take
care of, and best of all, it's light.
Perfect for carrying on long journeys.
But... to be able to fight against
sharpened metal with a wooden sword...
You demonstrate such proficient
qi channeling with such ease.
It's not easy at all!
It exhausts the hell out of me,
and takes a real toll internally.
I am totally wiped out.
You could just use a regular sword...
Why go to all this trouble?
Well, shouldn't it be troubling
to cut someone down?
No matter how great your skills are,
it should never be an casual,
simple matter to brandish a sword.
But when you're a slob to the core like me,
constantly being penitent
is too much of a pain.
Carrying a sword with
no edge is a lot easier.
Then Shā Wú Shēng thought your
sword was made of actual iron,
and underestimated you because
it lacked an edge?
You came from Xī Yōu,
which is why you didn't know
of the Screaming Phoenix Killer
and the Enigmatic Gale.
Well, yeah.
But if there was a hero who was
just as famous as them in Xī Yōu,
there'd be no way for us people from
Dōng Li to know about him, would there?
Are you actually...
Right now, I'm Shāng Bù
Huàn, the Edgeless Blade.
And that's fine with me.
Now, then... if you could,
Miss Hù Yìn Shī,
can you show me the way to the
Duàn Jiàn Cí  from here?
Even with no one to guard the sword,
the protective field is still in effect, eh?
It's good that I arrived
first, but this sensation...
Could it be that I've
underestimated Miè Tiān Hái?
His selfish ambition to take the Shén Huì
Mó Xiè from the care of the Hù Yìn Shī...
I had thought that arrogance
was what I needed to steal.
But is the Tiān Xing Jiàn really that
valuable to the Bones of Creation?
Is that really it?
Were you waiting long, Miè Tiān Hái?
No, I just arrived as well.
How did it go?
As you can see...
Splendid. Thanks to your cooperation,
I have been able to easily
outmaneuver the Enigmatic Gale.
You have my gratitude.
As long as the reward
demonstrates that gratitude...
That'll be just fine.
Now, the time has finally
come for my wish to come true!
There's something I need to ask you.
Yes, what is it?
The demon god that the Tiān Xing Jiàn
defeated in the War of Fading Dusk...
You're sure it was Yāo Tú Lí, right?
Yes, that is what the records say.
So, Yāo Tú Lí wasn't forced
back to the demon realm,
but was actually destroyed in our world?
No, that's...
Concepts like death and destruction do not
apply to demon gods in the first place.
Even if you destroy their form,
they can return in a new body.
That is why they are so fearsome.
Thus, the Shén Huì Mó Xiè
are weapons whose purpose is to force
them to return to the demon realm.
The Tiān Xing Jiàn is no exception.
So, Yāo Tú Lí should be
in the demon realm, right?
But it's not like you've been
there to confirm that.
Is something troubling you?
A little bit.
For now, let's just hurry on.
This is the Tiān Xing Jiàn!
Its power, which can
strike down a demon god...
Just how great will it be?
Now...
Awaken from your 200 years
of slumber, by my hand.
Tiān Xing Jiàn!
Wh-What is this shaking?!
What is that thing?!
Then it's true! It's as I suspected!
What is this, Xíng Hài?!
What is that monster down there?!
You should tremble... You should bow down!
What you see here is the
demon god, Yāo Tú Lí!
The incantation of destruction, long
thought to have been lost to oblivion!
Then he was not slain?
Don't be so conceited.
Do you think that we, who are
mythic and immortal gods,
can be wiped out by magical weapons cooked
up by a couple of mountain wizards?
How pitifully comical!
Forcing one such as him into
a state of persistent sleep
is the best your kind could have managed.
Then the Tiān Xing Jiàn's seal was not
simply to prevent the sword's removal,
but a means of keeping
the demon god contained?
I see, so that's the game here.
Bones of Creation!
Return the sword to its pedestal!
He's still asleep! There's still time!
What are you saying?
That demon god being let loose means
the return of the War of Fading Dusk!
All who live will be hunted down and killed!
You and I are no exception!
I'd rather you not interfere.
Xíng Hài!
Wh-What are you...
There was only one reason I sought
the Tiān Xing Jiàn with you fools.
To remove that wretched sealing sword
from the Duàn Jiàn Cí's pedestal!
X-Xíng...
Hài... you wretch!
I see.
Then this was your aim all along,
Xíng Hài, the Night's Lament?
The fate of Yāo Tú Lí
has long been a mystery to us demons.
The Hù Yìn Shī who erected this shrine...
I congratulate them on keeping
the secret for so long.
But in their desire to keep that secret,
they failed to let their descendants
know the nature of the shrine.
How supremely foolish.
Well, if the truth of the Tiān Xing
Jiàn's seal was common knowledge,
the Duàn Jiàn Cí's defenses
would not have fallen so easily
to the Xuán Guǐ Zōng, either.
But if that were the case,
we demons would have descended
upon this shrine en masse.
The humans made the right choice.
Even I, until I was certain of
the Tiān Xing Jiàn's nature,
was too afraid to take action.
If you've been acting in accordance
with your own agenda all along...
Then I needn't pay you for the guard.
Well, human, I now ask you this...
What will you do with that sword?
If I were to change my mind,
and choose to seal Yāo Tú Lí once more...
Then you would face me in battle.
A battle to determine the
fate of the human realm!
There's no need.
The return of a demon god? I welcome it.
A world of chaos is a one
where the sword rules supreme.
A fitting path for me to travel!
Foolish! Foolish in every detail!
This is why you humans are beyond help!
If I must seal Yāo Tú Lí,
let it be after he's wrought
havoc upon the world first.
Then, my name will be that of a savior...
And I will be worshiped as one.
I see. Then the next time
we meet, it will be as foes.
Very well.
I will correct your overconfidence
when we meet again!
Get to work, Xíng Hài.
I'm sure your mighty demon
god requires another ritual
before he can fully rouse
himself from his slumber.
If you don't hurry,
someone is likely to catch on.
Then we part for now, Bones of Creation.
Until we meet again,
amid the hellish pandemonium!
Now, I know you're there, Enigmatic Gale.
It's time to cease your eavesdropping.
Being admonished for something like that...
When I'm a thief in the
first place is a bit odd.
Behold! I already wield the Tiān Xing Jiàn.
And what of you, Lǐn Xuě Yā?
After crawling around in the shadows
and coming up with petty schemes...
What have you gained?
I happened to gain the answer
I needed while I was
eavesdropping on the roof.
Miè Tiān Hái, your ethos as a champion...
In other words, the nature of your
arrogance, is now clear to me.
That is the treasure which
I truly intend to steal.
Really?
You should have been disappointed to
learn the truth of the Tiān Xing Jiàn,
yet you don't seem discouraged at all.
In fact,
you're letting a demon god that could
destroy the world get free without a pause.
No disillusionment at your dream being
untrue, or fear of the future.
A man who solves all his problems
himself, and is thus, always satisfied.
That's who you are.
Your desires, your joy...
They are all deeply internal for you.
In other words, the ultimate
sword you speak of
is not a famous, miraculous
Shén Huì Mó Xiè...
But your swordplay, which
you have honed to greatness,
with few ever learning its nature.
You believe that your
technique reigns supreme,
and simply wanted the Tiān Xing
Jiàn as a weapon worthy of it.
Precisely! Undefeated and
unparalleled sword techniques
are the throne upon which my pride sits.
And that is not something that
some bandit can simply steal.
If my target is something that pedestrian,
there's no need for sophisticated methods...
Simply taking it by force
will more than suffice.
Next Time  "A New Duty"
A diabolic curse awakens.
A god speaks of encroaching annihilation.
The earth-shattering
fantasy nears its climax
with a battle to end it all!