Episode 9: "The Essence of a Sword"
He's a thief?
Then is the bastard—
Damn it all!
He's been after Miss Dān Fěi's
Tiān Xing Jiàn all along!
I...
Then I've been...
If you people knew all along,
why didn't you say something?!
Any number of reasons... right?
He was asking for help
to swindle one of the the Shén Huì Mó Xiè
from a little Hù Yìn Shī girl.
That's what the letters he sent us said.
That's what it said in the
letter to Lián Qí as well.
That's exactly what I'd expect
from a sneak thief like Lǐn Xuě Yā.
I wouldn't dismiss him
as a mere sneak thief.
Of all the Shén Huì Mó Xiè, the Tiān
Xing Jiàn is in a class of its own.
If you presented it to a
lord of the Demon Realm,
you'd receive more treasure
than you'd ever be able to spend
in the human realm in exchange.
So, that's why you agreed to join us.
Bro, why didn't you tell
me about any of this?!
I brought you along to see if you
would make a decent little brother.
I wasn't about to tell you.
In the end, you were the biggest
riddle, Shāng Bù Huàn.
You had no clue about the robbery,
but you don't seem like you're
serving the Hù Yìn Shī either.
I had no idea whose side you were on,
or why Lǐn Xuě Yā brought you along.
We've all been pondering that for a while.
But it seems like that was a waste of time.
The fact that you're in
this cage now means...
Whatever role Lǐn Xuě Yā had
for you has been fulfilled.
What do you mean, role?
Most likely a clown to get the Hù Yìn
Shī to lower her guard, I'd imagine.
It makes sense.
Even a ham of an actor
can manage an awkward laugh if you
put him on stage with no idea what to do.
This can't...
I trusted all of you!
The person you needed to suspect
the most was the one you didn't.
If you regret anything, regret the
fact that you lived long enough to meet him.
Once your tears run dry,
you'll become demon bird food.
Try to be so exhausted from your wailing
that you won't feel their fangs.
Are w-we just gonna leave
them in here?! Guys?
If you don't like it, then put
them out of their misery.
It'd be a kindness at this point.
Don't disappoint me, Cán Yún.
Didn't you come all this way
to learn from the One-Eyed Impaler?
The person you should've
suspected the most, huh?
I really screwed up there.
I got the impression I should've cut him
down the second I saw him, and yet...
If you don't mind me saying, I've never
encountered this sort of hospitality before.
This marks the third time we've met.
Oh?
Excuse me, but I believe
this is our first encounter.
We first met when you served
as chief guard in the capital.
Well, that can't be.
I'm sure it's just a passing resemblance.
The next time,
you claimed to be a gentlemen who was
preparing to enter civil service.
Another case of mistaken identity, I'm sure.
So stubborn.
As a master thief,
why not show some respect
to someone who's seen through your ruse?
Whatever do you mean?
This Tiān Xing Jiàn guard is a forgery.
Well, well, I must applaud
your eye, Bones of Creation.
Let's put aside the farce for now, then.
Your skill at crafting forgeries
remains godlike.
The rumors say that if you
see something for ten seconds
and touch it for five, you can
create a perfect imitation.
I had the opportunity to leisurely
observe my subject this time.
It's quite a fine forgery,
if I do say so myself.
While the forgery is remarkable,
the fact that you were able
to swap it with the original
without the Hù Yìn Shī girl
noticing is also of note.
When and how did you manage it?
Were I to tell you, I'd be giving you a
clue to the whereabouts of the original.
I'm not falling for that one.
Let's just say that it was sometime before
we arrived at the Demon Spine Mountains.
As shrewd as ever.
Why would a thief like you
steal a piece of the
Shén Huì Mó Xiè in the first place?
I'm fully aware the guard
holds no value on its own.
Only with the acquisition of the handle,
and the breaking of the seal
at the Duàn Jiàn Cí
can one truly claim the Tiān Xing Jiàn.
Then you intend to take the
Tiān Xing Jiàn's handle next?
There's a much more conservative
approach than that.
For instance, approaching
whoever holds the handle,
and seeing how much they'd pay for the guard.
That's not a very daring approach
for a thief infamous throughout the land.
When you balance the price of
the assembled Tiān Xing Jiàn
against the prospect of stealing the
handle from the Bones of Creation,
it's the obvious choice.
After all, I'm dealing with a man who
saw through my forgery at a glance.
And what's your asking price?
Five thousand jīn of gold.
That's quite the price.
For the price of one of the
genuine Shén Huì Mó Xiè,
I'd say it's quite the modest estimate.
That damned Lǐn Xuě Yā has
situated himself perfectly for now.
So what should we do?
That's a tough one.
There's no telling what kind
of show the Enigmatic Gale
will be putting on for
the Bones of Creation.
We probably can't even imagine.
But is it a good idea to
leave it entirely to him?
A good point.
Considering who we're talking about,
he could just do whatever
works the best for him.
For instance, instead of stealing
the Tiān Xing Jiàn's handle,
he might try selling the guard and
keeping the profits for himself.
Being a thief's partner must be
unpleasant, with all this tedium.
What?
It's truly pathetic.
You two can sit here and
dawdle until the sun sets.
But I'm not putting up with it.
Are you insane?
If you go in there, the Xuán Guǐ
Zōng will attack you en masse.
No number of those weaklings stands a chance.
It's time I settle my business.
Oh, that's right.
You weren't after the Tiān
Xing Jiàn, were you?
You're not going to get in my way, are you?
I see no reason for us to do that.
I can't imagine Xuě Yā
expects us to, either.
Go on.
Farewell, then.
Is this a good idea?
He intends to kill Xuě Yā.
I'm thinking we send Shā after Lǐn
to ensure he doesn't just do as he pleases.
Bro... is this really right?
Even if we get the treasure,
wouldn't these cowardly methods
bring shame on your name?
That won't happen.
No one's ever going to learn about
what happened in these mountains.
But what about your own pride?
None of this is honorable at all.
Doesn't that bother you?
Cán Yún, true pride is something that
you have to trade your very life for.
No matter how proud someone acts,
they have a secret shame.
If anything, the heroes whose
names go down in history
are just the ones who did the best
job of hiding their misdeeds.
But... but I thought you were
the real deal! A big hero!
And I can teach you exactly how
to give people that impression.
The first thing you need is to not
let idiotic sentimentality stop you.
I know you feel attracted
to the Hù Yìn Shī girl.
But forget about her.
You'll sacrifice many things for
the sake of glory, in the future.
Realize that she'll just
be the first of many.
That's...
You're still young.
Everyone has trouble taking that first step.
But once you do, you can
become like me one day.
I'm still renowned throughout the land
as the One-Eyed Impaler at my age.
Take my words to heart.
I remember when you laughed
at me before, Sir Shāng.
I asked you if you believed
in the goodness of people...
I understand now how exasperated
you must have felt.
The sacred grounds,
our clan's traditions,
and my loving family are
all I have ever known.
I never knew a thing
about the outside world,
yet I assumed everyone must value justice,
and never thought to doubt anyone else.
I should have never taken a
step outside the shrine...
and died alongside my brother.
At least that way I would have never
brought my troubles upon you as well.
You stay here for now.
I'm not ready to run yet.
So, I promise you... when I climb down from
these mountains, I'll bring you with me.
Sir Shāng...
It's still safer inside
that cage for the moment.
Bear with it for a little longer.
Sir Shāng, what do you intend to do?
It's time for payback.
Hey, I won't be long. Don't worry.
That's... But...
There's plenty of righteous people
who are easily tricked because of it.
You can regret being deceived,
but don't you regret trying
to do the right thing.
This is fantastic.
I'm amazed you were able to gather them all.
They will only hold their luster
until the Tiān Xing Jiàn
is placed among them.
In the presence of the legendary
Shén Huì Mó Xiè that slew
the demon god, Yāo Tú Lí,
even the most famous blades
will seem like scrap metal.
And the sword's handle?
In there.
Don't you dare ask to see it, now.
I'm not that careless.
Why are you fixated on swords?
Swords are the greatest symbol
of strength in the world.
They signify a truth that stands resolute.
The embodiment of the absolute
truth about life and death.
This is why I desire swords
of value and power.
Wealth, glory, and authority are
as fleeting as foam on the sea.
They are nothing compared to the joy
of taking hold of destruction's power itself.
I can't imagine any joy that would
make me trample holy ground
and murder others.
But what of you, Enigmatic Gale?
What does the greatest thief in
the land seek when he steals?
There's no grand rationale to it, in my case.
You can't deceive me.
Someone as clever as you
has countless means to amass wealth
without going to the trouble of stealing.
Yet you persist in your
transgressions against the law,
your undertaking of evil. Why?
Well, I suppose there are things in this
world that you can only obtain by stealing.
Oh, such as?
Formless things, things that
cannot even be appraised.
If I had to put it into words...
The only words that seem to fit
are the ethos of a champion.
The ethos of a champion?
What's this commotion?
M-Master, I'm so sorry!
We were unable to hold him back!
Good grief, Shā Wú Shēng.
It's a bit rude to barge in uninvited,
wouldn't you say?
I'm not here for a lecture
in etiquette from a thief.
Lǐn Xuě Yā, the time has come for
me to take your head, as you promised.
Wasn't I going to give it to you for guiding
me through the Labyrinth of Darkness?
But I didn't pass through the Labyrinth.
The deal is off.
You argue nonsense without a shred
of shame. Not that it matters.
There is nowhere for you to run.
It was important to me that
you had no means of escape.
And thankfully, this place is perfect.
A tower high in the mountains...
Unless you can fly, there is no way out!
Trapped like a rat, is that it?
Exactly.
Which is why I have no reason to rush
in administering death to Lǐn Xuě Yā.
Rather, my priority at the moment...
is you, Bones of Creation!
When I saw you at that riverside,
there was something I
knew I needed to ask you.
Then go right ahead.
I appreciate it.
Now, draw your sword!
Did you not have a question?
The Screaming Phoenix Killer does
not ask questions with words.
It is with my swords
and the gambles of fate
that I seek answers!
If you seek to question
essence of the sword,
then I suppose my creed
dictates that I must answer.
The answer always lies at the
brink of life and death.
You're wise to realize this,
Screaming Phoenix Killer.
Remarkable!
Eight moves...
No. In nine moves, it will end.
Indeed...
Three to test, five to press,
and the final ninth strike...
is the answer!
Why persist in the battle when
you're aware of the outcome?
My path of swordsmanship has
been one of inevitability.
If I realize I can not win,
I will not be satisfied
without tasting defeat.
Lǐn Xuě Yā...
I will be waiting ahead
in ambush, once again.
Even you cannot evade the afterlife forever.
I'll be waiting.
Right. Until we meet again, then.
Don't feed the body to the demon birds.
Show proper respect in its cremation.
Yes, sir.
Sad to see him go?
No.
He had long hoped to meet
someone stronger than he was.
I imagine he's pleased to have fallen here.
However...
I hadn't imagined you were a greater
swordsman than the Screaming Phoenix Killer.
He took a single glimpse at my stance
and took the measure of my strength.
I can see why he would be known as a
peerless master to the world at large.
As skilled as you are, you could
have risen to glory legitimately,
without the notoriety
of the Xuán Guǐ Zōng.
Demonstrating your sword technique
so frequently that you become renowned
for it is the height of carelessness.
A sword is at its most vital when
its nature remains concealed.
That is the difference between
myself and Shā Wú Shēng.
No interest in being hailed
as a great warrior, then?
My sword knows no match under the heavens,
whether it has earned a title or not!
Why bother seeking to test that fact?
We've prepared your room here.
Please, make yourself at home.
Right.
This is...
Next Time  "A Thief's Pride"
At the boundary of deception and truth,
a comical figure dances in shadow.
And inside of the trap it has set,
a white crow smiles coldly.