Episode 8  "The Enigmatic Gale"
From here on out, I'm going on my own.
I'm done with all of you!
Come now,
do you intend challenge the Labyrinth
of Darkness without the Soul Echo Flute?
That's supposed to be impossible,
right? So I'll find a different path.
We're almost to Seven Sins Tower, anyway.
Surely you can't be this insane.
So what if it's a little crazy?
How much crazy crap have you
had me doing this whole time?
This group you put together are
a bunch of useless lunkheads,
which leaves me to handle all the crazy jobs!
I'm even starting to doubt
that flute's any use.
I'm done listening to you.
If I'm taking on crazy odds, it'll be
a lot more pleasant to do it alone.
What now?
Well, his departure shouldn't
prove any inconvenience to us.
All we really need at this point
is the Soul Echo Flute, after all.
No, that won't do.
We need him to stay on until
the end, no matter what.
Why, exactly?
I'd love to hear an explanation.
Just who is he? How'd you come to know him?
Were you testing him at the previous
obstacles, just to find that out?
How ridiculous.
I thought you were all more
respectable than this.
Forsaking your responsibilities to play
such a nasty prank at a critical moment.
It's not like you stopped us.
Well, I can't deny that I was curious
to see what he was capable of.
I suppose I ended up going
along with it in the end.
A bad habit of mine.
That's terrible!
Then you weren't being serious?
In the wider world, it's natural
to wish to test the mettle of others.
But this is too much! He was
fighting so desperately.
I'm going to look for him!
Hey, wait!
Oh, it'll be dangerous for you
to go alone. I will go as well.
Well, what do you think?
Hard to say, when we don't
know why he brought that
Shāng Bù Huàn along in the first place.
If he refuses to abandon Bù Huàn,
there's definitely a larger scheme in play.
We still don't know who
that man really is, too.
He had impressive bursts
of power in his strikes.
And even in the Valley of the Dead,
against such superior numbers,
he moved in a way that left no openings.
But... despite that, his sword
techniques were quite unsightly.
Huh? Wait, why?
The wounds he dealt those
corpses lacked sharpness.
Considering he was facing rotted corpses,
blows with a third of the force
he used would've been enough.
He wasn't in enough danger to
be fighting that desperately.
It was the same way in
the Valley of the Doll.
With that kind of persistent
power in his blows,
stone or not, his blade could
have penetrated his foe.
When first-rate sword skill is matched
with first-rate striking force,
a blade can split steel, not just flesh.
Facing that stone doll,
if he had not been intimidated by its size
and instead watched it carefully,
he could've cut the heel of its
foot to hobble its movement.
But he instead chose to run.
Which means he most likely lacks
confidence in his swordplay, right?
So he's a skilled warrior,
but not first-rate.
He mastered a technique for
striking with blunt force,
but is now pretending to be
a swordsman for some reason.
He might be a riddle,
but if he turns against us,
he won't pose that much of a threat.
Abandoning him won't be a problem.
But is it really likely he'd betray us?
When we consider who brought him
into this group, most definitely.
There's no way to know
what he's actually after.
Okay, you're talking about
Mister Guǐ Niǎo, right?
He's my bro's old acquaintance, isn't he?
Oh, the boy only knows him as Guǐ Niǎo.
Something to remember:
the infamous names in this world
don't always have an infamous face attached.
If anything, the ones who
keep their appearance hidden
are more shrewd and more dangerous.
Lady Dān Fěi, please wait!
It's dangerous to act alone!
You people are too cruel!
Treating someone so
earnest like he's a toy...
You're quite right.
I fully intend to make
amends to Shāng Bù Huàn.
And to do that, we first
need to bring him back.
But where could he have gone?
Sir Shāng?
Shhh! Keep quiet.
What are they doing?
I see.
They're likely trying to catch
and tame additional demon birds.
Yeah, they use those things to get
to and from Seven Sins Tower, right?
This could be our chance!
What do you mean?
If we grab some of their demon birds,
we can use them to fly to the summit,
without having to worry about
the Labyrinth of Darkness.
Quite the clever improvisation from the
reckless daredevil, Shāng Bù Huàn.
Shut up, man.
The demon birds are sorcerous
creatures, unlike cows or horses.
Controlling them will require
some kind of enchanted tool.
Let us take a closer look at the
belongings of these Xuán Guǐ Zōng.
All right, we'll take them
down with a surprise attack!
That was easy.
Now, for a quick look.
What is that thing?
This is a wind-whistle made
from demon bird bones.
You throw it, and the passage
of air creates the sound.
You gonna be okay?
Don't panic.
As long as you have the whistle,
these creatures can't tell who you are.
There, there, good boy.
Never loses his cool, does he?
Then there's just a matter
of thought transference.
Simply think that you want them to "return."
Try to avoid unnecessary thoughts.
R-Right.
Is that...
I guess we're the ones who were left behind.
Then what do we do?!
We follow them, of course.
If it's this easy, we should've done this to
get to Seven Sins Tower in the first place!
Don't let any wicked thoughts
enter your mind during flight.
A mistake with these demon birds can
send into the ground upside-down.
Well, it's not far,
so we should be fine
despite our lack of practice.
But hanging from them for too
long might prove dangerous.
That's Seven Sins Tower.
Hey, are we really gonna be
okay just flying in like this?
I had thought it would be convenient to
avoid the Labyrinth of Darkness,
but hadn't considered much beyond that.
Now, what shall we do?
At this point, we simply need
to brace ourselves for battle.
You think they've noticed us?
Hopefully not, but...
Do not insult me.
Do you think we do not know how to
treat guests at Seven Sins Tower?
Dammit! They were waiting for us!
I suppose we've fallen into a trap.
How did you find your flight
with the demon birds?
Well, consider that a reward
for your performances at the
Valley of the Dead and
the Valley of the Doll.
After all, I'd hate for the
Tiān Xing Jiàn's guard to
fall into the Labyrinth of Darkness
after coming all this way.
How much must you underestimate me
before you are satisfied, you cur?!
With my Dān Blade Techniques,
I will cut short your conceit!
With my brother's grief guiding my sword!
Hey, wait!
Please, don't stop me!
I endured the entire journey for this moment!
I must deliver divine punishment
to this man, no matter what!
You speak with remarkable boldness.
It's such a shame that you were born a woman.
Very well. Xuán Guǐ Zōng, do not interfere.
All matters with this girl will be accounted
for in a contest between the two of us!
Yes, sir.
Prepare yourself!
It's working! My sword is effective!
My rage and my brother's will
are giving me the strength!
With this attack, I will have my revenge!
Dān Blade Technique: Yang Sunrise!
You're finished!
Whoa! What the hell are you doing?!
Be silent! I will have
vengeance for my brother!
Master, what is this?!
Such a sly trick.
Guǐ Niǎo! You did it again, didn't you?!
What the hell are you getting at?!
Unlike the Bones of Creation,
we don't need to worry about your
sword harming Lady Dān Fěi.
What would you prefer?
That we watch her die pointlessly in
a battle she has no chance of winning?
But why do it this way?!
Drop your weapon!
Master...
Here it is.
Well, now...
Is something the matter?
I see.
Damn you! This is quite the trick
you've pulled, Enigmatic Gale!
Enigmatic what, now?
Throw the two of them into cages.
Yes, sir!
Hey, Guǐ Niǎo, what
are you trying to pull?!
Silence!
What a mess... with all this wind,
I can't even relax and sleep.
Well, I guess being out in the open is
nicer than being in some musty dungeon.
Is the idea that we're gonna
freeze to death by morning?
Oh, I get it.
When we die, we become demon bird food.
Saves them the trouble of
cleaning up the bodies.
Kind of a lazy approach for
the lord of a castle.
Where are we?
Hey, you awake now?
I was fighting Miè Tiān Hái, then...
What in the world has happened?
No need to remember all the details.
The bottom line is, we were captured.
And now we're helpless as
helpless as caged birds
Where is Sir Guǐ Niǎo?
Well about that...
I don't really know how to explain it,
but we were caught because of him.
Oh, no! Please, what happened, exactly?
I don't really get it, either.
But when it came down to it, he betrayed us.
The guard!
Where is the Tiān Xing Jiàn's guard?!
For now, we should be
grateful we're still alive.
I couldn't avenge my brother.
And I even lost the guard.
I don't know how to make
this up to my ancestors!
You shouldn't have come here if you really
wanted to keep the Tiān Xing Jiàn safe.
Yes... I know.
With my brother gone,
it was ridiculous to think
someone as inexperienced as I could
fulfill our duty as Hù Yìn Shī.
If the Xuán Guǐ Zōng were
always going to hunt me down,
leaving me nowhere to go...
I should have traded my
life in exchange for dealing
a killing blow to that
wretched Miè Tiān Hái.
I've been so foolish!
Even if I had sacrifice my own petty life,
what could it have accomplished?
Hey! Damn it!
Are you picking on Miss Dān Fěi
and making her cry again?!
No!
Wait, how are you even here?!
Don't be such a simpleton.
We simply used the Soul Echo Flute to
get through the Labyrinth of Darkness.
If you had just kept quiet
and followed along,
you wouldn't be in such sorry shape.
That's what happens when you're
impatient and take shortcuts!
Just hang on a sec,
and we'll get you out of there!
Wha...?
Bro?
Where's Guǐ Niǎo?
Was he not captured with you?
That's the weird thing.
As soon as Miè Tiān Hái showed up,
he cast an illusion on Dān Fěi
to get her to attack me.
I see.
Instead of standing against
the Xuán Guǐ Zōng,
he intends to ingratiate himself to them.
Well, that does sound like the
kind of strategy he'd use.
What do you mean?
Instead of taking the Tiān Xing
Jiàn's handle with force,
he intends to wait for
the chance to steal it.
To do that, he makes a gesture
towards its master...
And is invited to the tower as a guest.
There's no way it'd work that easily!
Except it did, and now you're
in there as a result.
He sold the two of you out to
put himself at an advantage,
by earning Miè Tiān Hái's trust.
Wait a minute! This doesn't add up!
He came this far to help Dān Fěi, right?
If it's for the Tiān Xing Jiàn,
what sense does it make to betray her?
To still be spouting this nonsense...
You actually came along without
knowing anything, didn't you?
I never imagined it'd be
this big a disappointment.
I thought you might've been forced
by the Enigmatic Gale to cooperate,
but in the end...
You really are just some vagabond.
The Enigmatic Gale?!
Then that really is Guǐ Niǎo's other name?
Oh... Oh, no...
Then Sir Guǐ Niǎo is... Lǐn Xuě Yā?!
Who, now?
I spent my entire life in a sanctuary,
and even I've heard his name.
He's an infamous thief, a master of
treachery who comes and goes like a phantom.
It's said that if he sets
his sights on your treasure,
there is no way to prevent
him from taking it.
He's a thief?
Then is the bastard—
Dammit all!
He's been after Miss Dān Fěi's
Tiān Xing Jiàn all along!
Subterfuge is not always
about lurking in the darkness.
Some shadows remain hidden in the light.
A hair's breadth separates truth from lies.
And none will gaze beyond the
illusion to see my true face.
Next Time  "The Essence of a Sword"
When faced with danger and empty hands,
one must sharpen the fangs of the soul.
The supernatural blade
was used to banish chaos,
but to whom will the sword
of judgment fall?