Episode 10: "A Thief's Pride"
Now, Guǐ Niǎo... or I guess,
Lǐn Xuě Yā... Where is the bastard?
What's the commotion?
It's like an endless
river of cannon fodder.
If you don't want to die,
take me to the Enigmatic Gale.
Shā Wú Shēng?
Oh yeah, he said he was going to kill
Lǐn as soon as he reached the tower.
Damn you... don't falter! Attack!
Fools.
You think your greater numbers can
halt the Screaming Phoenix Killer?
Well, him making all this
racket works out great for me.
Gonna borrow this for a bit.
Damn, this place is so huge,
I don't know where to look.
But considering how mad Shā Wú Shēng looked,
Lǐn might already have been put down.
That'd be fine by me.
Whoa!
We've prepared your room here.
Please, make yourself at home.
Right.
This is...
Glad you noticed.
Killing you from behind would've
made me feel guilty later.
Kill me and the Tiān Xing Jiàn
stays with Miè Tiān Hái.
Hm?
The guard he has is a forgery.
I still have the genuine article.
And I'll be stealing the handle next.
It's possible, if we work together.
You really think I'm gonna help
you obtain the Tiān Xing Jiàn?
The opposite.
I will be helping you return
the Tiān Xing Jiàn,
so that you can face Lady Dān Fěi again.
That sounds pretty different from what
you told Yún Xiāo and Xíng Hài.
I just told them what I needed
to get them to help us
cross the Demon Spine Mountains.
Now that we're at Seven Sins Tower,
I've no further use for them.
And me? Why'd you bring me here, exactly?
The One-Eyed Impaler and the Night's
Lament are unrepentant villains.
They'd both use any chance to abandon me,
and take the sword for their own.
Which is where... you enter the picture.
"Where did he come from?"
The mere presence of someone whose
connection to me wasn't clear
would put them on guard and afford them
little chance to scheme against me.
You were just the advantage I needed.
Are you kidding? It sounds
like I was just a distraction!
I have my own complaints
about that, believe me.
If I had known you had the skills
to clear the Valley of the Dead
and the Valley of the Doll by yourself,
I wouldn't have had to invite Shòu Yún
Xiāo and Xíng Hài along in the first place.
I had no idea you had mastered
such a dreadful sword.
Why not tell me in the beginning?
Don't try and make it sound
like I was the one holding out.
If I'd known I was working with a
thief to steal the Shén Huì Mó Xiè,
I never would've come along!
As I keep saying...
I have no desire for the Tiān Xing Jiàn.
My target is Miè Tiān Hái.
What?
I simply want to ruin his desperate
search for the ultimate sword.
The fact that this involves the
Tiān Xing Jiàn enshrined at
the Duàn Jiàn Cí is a coincidence.
You have some kinda grudge against him?
I don't mind explaining,
but... do you really care?
If you want me to trust you, then hand
over the Tiān Xing Jiàn's guard.
It's not here.
I hid it someplace safe.
Then tell me where it's hidden.
Do you remember Limitless Temple?
Where I planned on meeting up with Master
Lián Qí, and we ran into Shā Wú Shēng.
I hid it in the stone path.
You had already swiped it
from Dān Fěi back then?
Yet you didn't have a hint
of guilt on your face.
Well, if I did,
I wouldn't be much of a thief.
You might even be lying to me
without blinking an eye right now.
It's up to you whether or not you believe me.
My life or the Tiān Xing Jiàn.
Which do you want more?
What if I want both?
Then I'd say you have to leave me alive
until you retrieve the sword's guard.
Unless you have a plan to break into
Miè Tiān Hái's safe on your own, that is.
Regardless, you should stay here until
the theft has been properly set up.
You should be safe in here.
I can't do that just yet.
I still have business outside.
Come on, don't do anything reckless!
If they find you, this will
all have been for nothing.
I'm not gonna screw up. I'll be right back.
Master Shāng! I'm glad you're all right.
Thought you might be a little
uneasy without a weapon.
So I grabbed your sword.
Picked up something to eat
from the kitchen, too.
How did you manage this?
The situation's changed a bit.
There might be a way to take the
Tiān Xing Jiàn's handle back.
First, about the guard. The one
Miè Tiān Hái took was a fake.
The real one was hidden by
Lǐn Xuě Yā a while ago.
It's in the stone path,
back at Limitless Temple.
That's...
When did he manage to do that?
In other words, before we got there,
he had already swapped it for the fake,
back when you were holding it.
What a dreadful man!
Beyond that...
Lǐn says he wants to steal the handle.
Seems to be something personal for him.
He also says he doesn't care about the
Tiān Xing Jiàn if he can put
one over on Miè Tiān Hái.
He's saying he'll give it back to you.
Sir Shāng, do you believe
what he's claiming?
Can't say for sure,
but the fact is, there's no way to get
the handle back save trusting him.
The Enigmatic Gale...
He casts no shadow when
he walks in the moonlight,
and leaves no footprints
when walking on snowy paths.
He finds ways to even
deceive the laws of nature.
A master thief, hatching and
undertaking dangerous plots...
His name has gone beyond rumor
and into the realm of legend.
So much that even I, who had never left
the sacred grounds, have heard of him.
Don't you fear the thought
that he might be manipulating you?
Well, if it turns out he's lying,
I can always just cut him
down when I find out.
That being the case, you're gonna
have to wait here a bit longer.
I know it's not the most comfortable place.
You gonna be okay?
Please, don't worry about me.
I don't know when I'll
next be able to come by.
You might feel hungry,
but try to make that food last.
See you later.
Five thousand jīn of gold...
I'll get it ready.
That is good to hear!
How will we handle the payment?
It'd be impossible to carry all that
gold down from this mountain.
I'd like you to prepare
it for me somewhere else.
Including two carts to move it all.
Such a cumbersome demand.
I'm sure the Xuán Guǐ Zōng
have the resources and methods to handle
things away from this mountain, right?
It's not that we lack.
But five thousand jīn is
a massive amount of gold.
It will take a full day to prepare it.
That's no problem.
I can enjoy this wonderful
wine in the meantime.
And how will I receive the guard?
First, we'll leave the mountain together,
and I'll confirm the payment.
Then, from there, I'll personally
take you to where it is hidden.
What guarantee do I have that you won't
simply take your payment and run?
In order to keep you from worrying
about something like that,
I'm saying I will take you there
immediately after being paid.
I may be an infamous thief,
but do you think I have a means to run
and hide while carrying
five thousand jīn of gold?
I see. That makes sense.
For the trip down,
I'd like to request a
gentle-natured demon bird.
If I were to fall during the flight,
you'd be out of luck.
You're a guest who makes a lot of requests.
But, no matter. I will
see to the preparations.
Then, let us toast to the new
owner of the Tiān Xing Jiàn.
The deal is set up.
Things are about to start moving.
Yeah? So what do we do, then?
In order to break into the
Bones of Creation's safe,
we'll need to draw him
outside of Seven Sins Tower.
So, I've invited him down off
the mountain under the pretense
of exchanging the guard for payment.
Whoa, hang on!
Are you opening the safe, or leaving
the mountain with Miè Tiān Hái?
Just which is it?
Put simply, we'll need a Lǐn
Xuě Yā to retrieve the payment,
and a Lǐn Xuě Yā to crack the safe.
This requires me to be in two places.
What stupid crap is this?
The thing with strategy...
is that unless someone laughs and says
it's ridiculous upon hearing about it,
it won't be enough to deceive the wise.
Put this hood on.
What is it?
Wh-What the hell?!
Breathe... I can't breathe, man!
What is this?!
Calm down. It won't kill you.
Convenient, isn't it?
Although, unfortunately, all it does is
let someone change their face into mine.
But that's enough to create
two of Lǐn Xuě Yā.
Well, this is one hell of a thing.
So? Which one of us does what?
The bigger risk lies in luring Miè
Tiān Hái outside of the tower.
That person will need to be prepared
to flee, eventually, after all.
But next you're gonna say that the person
who stays at the tower needs to know
how to get into the safe, right?
In other words, I've gotta do the crappy job.
It's a relief to see you're
so quick to understand.
Still, though...
Do you have some doubts?
You not caring about the Tiān Xing Jiàn
and saying that you'll be satisfied
as long as you dupe Miè Tiān Hái...
When that includes throwing away
five thousand jīn of gold,
it's a little hard to swallow.
Do you have a huge grudge
against him or something?
Oh, hardly.
I'd never really even spoken to
him before coming to this tower.
Then why?
Well, if I had to put it in words,
it's about how I find meaning in life.
To me, life is about amusement.
And the greatest game in this world...
is to deceive, manipulate, and outwit
someone: the game of strategy.
However,
it's far too simple to trick the noble
and good-natured, so that's no fun at all.
So if I'm going to deceive someone,
let them be a villain.
And a cunning, ambitious one at that.
Someone who's certain he's stronger and
smarter than everyone else is perfect.
In other words, everything is
just a game to you, is that it?
The heart of evil often beats in the
chest of the childishly sincere.
To take the source of his pride,
and replace the gem of arrogance with
the worthless rock of humiliation...
That speaks to my nature as a thief.
It's the thrill of a lifetime.
So you wanting t take something
from Miè Tiān Hái?
Yes, that's right.
The Bones of Creation seems to be the
exact character I had him pegged as.
Arrogantly calling himself unrivaled after
defeating the Screaming Phoenix Killer...
That makes for an irresistible jewel.
One worthy of being
stolen by the Enigmatic Gale.
Then the reason that Xíng Hài and
Shā Wú Shēng hated you so much...
Was it...?
That's right.
They're both the epitome
of villainy, and as such,
their arrogance was that
much greater than average.
Once I stole from them, the loss
of their doubt and obsession
was enough to result in those two
living out their days quietly.
If anything, I should probably be
praised for doing such a thing.
You're a real piece of work.
So... do you understand?
Yeah, I understand that you're
way too crazy to ever understand.
No sane person could figure
out what's going on with you,
and you're a genuine, irredeemable crook!
Should I be taking that as a compliment?
Miss Dān Fěi! You okay?
You!
Not so loud.
Well, I doubt anyone is coming,
but it doesn't hurt to be careful.
Huh? Careful about what?
I came to save you.
Let's get out of here together.
But I thought you...
I've cut ties to Shòu
Yún Xiāo and the others.
I'm not treating that guy as my
big brother or anything else!
The hero I looked up to was a fake.
Which means I have to become
the real deal myself, right?
I had the wrong idea this whole time.
Maybe with someone like you,
I can believe that there is some
justice in society at large again.
Whoa, it's not that big a deal!
I mean, I just wanna get famous, remember?
Then the story of the hero who
saved a Hù Yìn Shī in peril...
will be one I tell wherever
I go, from now on.
The heroic tale of the Frozen
Wonder and his spear!
That sounds like a pretty good opening act!
Come on, let's go.
Wait a moment!
Sir Shāng asked me to remain here until
he retrieved the Tiān Xing Jiàn's handle.
Yeah, now that you mention it,
I guess he isn't here...
But get it back? What's he gonna do alone?
Well... he says that Lǐn
Xuě Yā will be helping.
What?! That's just stupid!
Lǐn is one of the bad guys who's
after the sword in the first place!
You sure he's not just working with
the big thief to steal the sword?
I don't... want to believe he's
that kind of person, but...
Even if Shāng is playing straight,
that just makes it more likely the
Enigmatic Gale will trick him into whatever!
It's like a lost sheep asking
a tiger for directions!
I suppose you're right.
Look, I understand you wanna
get your treasure back,
and I'd love to help, but the
odds here are just terrible.
There's a bunch of different
crooks on this mountain,
all of them looking for a
chance to grab that sword!
Let's run for now.
And then we can get some help
from another Hù Yìn Shī
and give it another shot, later.
Well...
Right! The guard is still safe.
The one in Miè Tiān Hái's
clutches was a forgery.
H-How'd that happen?!
The true guard to the Tiān Xing
Jiàn is hidden at Limitless Temple.
If we can retrieve it first,
we can ensure the sword does not
fall into the hands of evil.
I'm not sure I get it but... that means
we have a chance to turn this around.
Okay! All the more reason to get
down off this mountain, and quick!
But how?
Without Shā Wú Shēng's flute,
there's no way to cross
the Labyrinth of Darkness.
It's okay! When we were going through
the Labyrinth with the flute,
I made a few markings to show the way.
We shouldn't get lost on the way back.
You seem like you are
completely thoughtless.
But you are actually quite considerate.
I guess I'll take that as a compliment!
Sir Lǐn, we're ready to depart.
The master is waiting for you.
Oh, of all the timing...
Is something the matter?
Sadly, I managed to tear my clothes, and
now I don't have the time to repair them.
I'm sorry, but could you get
me something else to wear?
Right away.
I'll leave the clothes here,
so if you could, please get ready quickly.
Thank you.
All right, time to do this.
Those clothes are a little too obvious...
Switch into these clothes first.
Got it.
This hood makes my shoulders stiff.
You never run out of complaints, do you?
What do I do once Miè hands over the gold?
Whatever you like. Just try and get
them to chase you as far as possible.
By the time they realize what's
going on, I'll have finished my job,
and fled the Demon Spine Mountains.
When you do, make sure you
take Dān Fěi with you!
You got that?
Lady Dān Fěi...
Here's hoping she hasn't
become demon bird food yet.
I'm just joking!
Who reacts to jest
with bloodlust? Honestly...
We've a sweet young girl
trapped, cold, and hungry!
I don't find that funny!
You are quite the character.
For all your attempts to seem aloof,
you can't hide your kind nature.
Man, shut up!
All right, I'm going. Don't screw this up!
Let's hope neither of us does.
Now, then...
Next Time  "A Proud Life"
In pursuit of fame and fortune,
one finds himself in a barren wilderness.
Where does the shining star that once
inspired such passion sit in
the vast darkness of the sky?