Episode 4: The Whereabouts of the Soul Echo Flute
Hey! This seems less like a
negotiation and more like a raid!
Her treatment of guests is a bit hard-edged.
Which means we'll need to knock on
her door in a suitably rough fashion.
This isn't going to end
unless we find Xíng Hài!
So where is she?
Could this be her idea of hide-and-seek?
There's no end to them!
All right, leave this to me.
You can control fire?!
Just a simple trick using a bit of gunpowder.
Although I haven't quite had enough practice
to make it suitable for an audience.
A slip of the hand,
and the whole area could
be engulfed in flames.
Oops...
This is crazy!
And so...
I can't imagine you'd prefer your
forest being burnt down, right?
Would you please come
forth and hear me out...
Xíng Hài, dear?
You filthy cur!
Of all the nerve...
You dare show yourself before me?!
Hello, Xíng Hài. It's been quite some time.
It's good to see you again.
The fact that I have to
look at your face again
makes me feel my entrails
being scorched with rage!
Whoa, there. Is it just me or does
she really, really hate you?
Come now. For demonic beings,
this is like exchanging pleasantries.
I sent a letter for you the other day,
but it seems you never received it.
That left me no choice but
to call upon you in person.
I received your message.
And I ignored it.
I will never...
Ever get involved with you again.
I'd think you could understand that!
Now, don't be that way.
You could at least hear me out.
Silence!
After everything that's happened,
do you think I would ever
be foolish enough to let
you manipulate me again?!
Back then, because of your deception...
Do you realize what I lost?!
Oh...
So that's how it is with you two.
The fact that I underestimated you
because you were a child of man,
and not even 100 years old...
Looking back on it, I want
to curse my lack of caution.
You could search the depths of the
demon realm for a villain like you,
and come up empty-handed!
Well, I'm really looking
forward to hearing about
what exactly happened with her later on.
Putting aside nostalgic
reminiscences for the moment,
you are, ultimately, a demon.
I can't imagine it'd be convenient for
you if one of the sealed mystic weapons
was unleashed upon the world.
In the human realm, your choices for
places to dwell are already limited.
Imagine how much worse it could get.
The mystic weapons that
are left in this era...
Almost all are mere shades of their
former glory, or imitations.
I have nothing to fear from them.
If Miè Tiān Hái has set
his sights on this one,
it would be wisest to assume it's
the authentic Tiān Xing Jiàn.
The Tiān Xing Jiàn?!
Then the weapon you spoke
of in your letter...
It's the Tiān Xing Jiàn blade,
sealed within the Duàn Jiàn Cí?
None other.
Well, then...
You should have said so
sooner, my dear friend.
If the Tiān Xing Jiàn's seal
is on the verge of being broken,
I can hardly ignore that.
You have my help,
in whatever way I can offer it.
Whoa, this is totally different
from what you were saying before!
I thought you hated this Guǐ Niǎo guy?
You humans, with your pitiably
short-sighted nature.
You're comparing a mountain and a mole hill.
My vendetta against this man
is of no consequence compared
to the Tiān Xing Jiàn.
So, Guǐ Niǎo, is it?
That's what you're calling yourself?
Yes, I'd appreciate it if
you would go with that.
Very well, then.
And I can assume the other matters
are as you wrote in your letter?
Yes, as we head to Demon Spine Mountain,
we'll need your power to
cross the Valley of the Dead.
Even the dead who still roam the Earth
can be put to rest with the
singing of the Night's Lament.
Isn't that right?
A simple matter.
You can consider me on
board for this venture.
Wh-What happened?!
We've come to an agreement.
Lady Xíng Hài will be
joining us on our journey.
I care little for the conflicts of humans,
but if the Tiān Xing Jiàn is involved,
that's another matter entirely.
You should be grateful.
Hey, hang on a second!
Where does a demon get off
being so haughty towards a Hù Yìn Shī?!
H-Hey!
I am grateful for your assistance.
My descendants will no doubt hear
tales of your generosity for generations.
You're okay with this?
Frustrated as I may be, the truth remains.
This danger is entirely due
to the Dān clan being unable
to fulfill its duty.
Sh-She's so noble...
If all humans were this charming,
perhaps this realm would be more pleasant.
Wouldn't you say, Guǐ Niǎo?
All of my friends are quite charming.
I can introduce you to more, if you'd like.
Something about the way
you said that irritates me.
Still, you're amazing, Mister Guǐ Niǎo!
I never figured you'd win over
Xíng Hài, the Night's Lament!
I'm still not sure about this.
Hey, man, I just don't buy
the way this is playing out.
Would she really just
change her tune so easily?
She was ready to kill Guǐ
Niǎo just a few moments ago.
It makes some sense.
It goes to show how much the Tiān
Xing Jiàn matters to the demon.
And you buy that?
The more clever the villain,
the quicker they are to adjust.
And that goes double for an
arch-villain like Xíng Hài.
But my point is...
Teaming up with an arch-villain
seems like a bad idea to me.
Then why'd you team up with Guǐ Niǎo?
I guess he really is a villain, then?
You haven't known him for long, have you?
With how shady things are looking now,
I'm starting to think I
should've gone on my own.
Oh, don't be so cold.
Our preparations for climbing the Demon
Spine Mountains are going smoothly.
All that's left is Master
Lián Qí's flute...
And our road to Seven
Sins Tower will be open.
And who's this Master Lián Qí?
One of my teachers.
He's a master of infusing
tools with sorcerous power.
Consider my pipe.
It has several uses beyond
its intended purpose.
Seems that way...
I learned how to create tools
like this from Master Lián Qí.
Convenient, right?
So this flute that gets us
through the labyrinth...
The Soul Echo Flute is one
of his greatest works.
And the old fellow is quite
skilled with a sword, too.
He'd be a wonderful boost
to our strength if he joined us.
You certainly do know many
people, Sir Guǐ Niǎo.
I mean, he even has a demon on his side!
Talk about impressive!
Do you have some sort of problem with that?
N-No, not at all.
If he has received the letter,
we should be meeting my master
at Limitless Temple in 3 days.
We ended up having to
take a bit of a detour...
So we should make haste for now.
Good grief...
These long trips do quite a
number on an old man's bones.
But at this rate, I should be
able to make the appointed time.
You're Lián Qí, aren't you?
Well, now...
I am indeed, but...
I can't imagine a reason why
the Screaming Phoenix Killer
would be looking for me.
It should be enough to tell you
this involves the Enigmatic Gale.
Ridiculous...
You're still after him?
I seek out anyone...
who might know where he's hiding.
And that includes me?
The answer should be obvious enough.
Come now...
I thought you were here
to ask me where he is.
What sense does it make to
draw your sword before asking?
The odds that you still have some
connection to him are high.
Furthermore, the odds that you are
headed to see him are equally high.
Then let's suppose the likelihood
of a clue to where you're headed
being among your belongings.
Together, that all makes it extremely
likely you have what I need.
More than enough reason to
kill you just to find out.
Just as you'd expect from the
Screaming Phoenix Killer, Shā Wú Shēng.
Your nonsense reasons for murder are
as numerous as stars in the sky.
Did it not occur to you to simply ask me?
If you were the type to
simply answer when asked...
That man would never tell you where he was.
That makes sense.
But you haven't just been going around
murdering acquaintances of his on that logic,
have you?
Whenever I've heard rumors
of someone who knows him...
I've killed them, to see what would happen.
Whether or not any of them
actually did know him...
That hardly matters now,
and there's no way to find out.
If it meant being hated by a beast like you,
he should've just killed
you when he had the chance.
That whelp never manages
to clean up his own mess.
He took something from me that
matters more than my life.
And no matter how many lives I take,
it still fails to equal what he stole!
Nonsense.
All that must mean is that your own
life doesn't carry enough value!
I suppose a master's duty is to correct
his student's careless mistakes!
You leave me no choice...
Now, come!
The Screaming Phoenix Killer...
To think you'd be this dangerous...
Curse you...
How could the heavens see fit
to grant such extraordinary
strength to a man like this?!
No begging for your life in the end?
Now I'm more sure than ever
that you knew him well.
It seems I've found quite the prize.
This old man, on this day...
He traveled this road
just so I could kill him.
You won't escape this time...
Enigmatic Gale.
Your fate is Shā Wú Shēng's to decide!
Is this it? The place where you'll meet
with that master you mentioned?
Yes...
We're later than I expected.
Hopefully he waited.
Hey, looks like he's here!
The smell of this place is offensive.
I'll be waiting here.
I guess when you're a demon,
incense must stink!
We'll be back soon.
Is that...?
Oh, damn!
Is that Sir Lián Qí?
No, I don't think so. But who is he?
You haven't heard of the
Screaming Phoenix Killer?!
Seriously, what country are you from?!
I don't know who he is, but I
can tell he's way too dangerous.
That's the kind of person you
should avoid messing with.
Sharp of you.
But Guǐ Niǎo can't avoid him this time.
The question is how he intends to do this.
This flute is supposed to hold
some labyrinth-conquering magic.
But it's second-rate as an instrument.
There's no elegance to its tune.
What happened to Master Lián Qí?
The answer to that is obvious.
His flute is all that's here...
And I am the Screaming Phoenix Killer.
The rest should be obvious
enough, shouldn't it?
As cruel as ever.
Are you not satisfied unless you
leave a trail of corpses behind you?
So...
Any interest in avenging your teacher?
That'd be exactly what you want.
I doubt my master, lying in the shade of the
grass somewhere, would want to see you happy.
As cold-hearted as I remember.
Not a single consideration
for your debts to him.
It's true that I don't believe in revenge.
But I can't leave that Soul
Echo Flute in your hands.
That suits me fine.
That means you have no choice
but to cross swords with me.
You think that's the only way?
I've dedicated this last year exclusively
to the task of killing you.
You escaped many times, but not today.
Because this flute that you need so badly...
is in my hands.
I don't really want to get involved
with whatever this fight's about,
but I can't have you killing
that man right now.
But he is going to die right now.
If that's a problem for you,
then you can die first...
Sharp-Eyed Impaler!
Don't be so cocky!
You're outnumbered two-to-one!
Don't do it!
But we need to help Sir Guǐ Niǎo!
Do not draw your sword around
that man. No matter what.
Sir Shāng, what do you mean?
Too late!
Such an obvious attack.
Where are you trying to lead me?
To your place of dying! Where else?!
Who's going to die and where, exactly?
Bro—!
You're a lively one, boy.
What's your name?
Juǎn Cán Yún!
They call me the Frozen Wonder of the Spear!
Remember that!
Right, I won't forget.
At least, while you still live.
So fast—!
Killer Strike: Hundred Flock Morning Phoenix!
No—
Now you die!
I was wondering what the delay was...
What are you playing at with this fool?
Xíng Hài, the Night's Lament?
Another odd one in your company.
What now?! It's three-on-one!
Three of you?
You think that, facing me,
your numbers hold any meaning?
Wait! Let's withdraw.
Wha—
What are you saying, Mister Guǐ Niǎo?!
He's not just going to let us leave!
No. As long as he holds the Soul Echo Flute,
he has us right where he wants us,
no matter where we go.
Isn't that right, Wú Shēng?
Indeed.
There's no need for me to rush.
I'll be staying at the near
the devilwood flower garden.
If you want the flute, you can
come for it whenever you please.
Hey, hey, hey!
Why would you let him go?!
It means you get to live another day.
How can you be so scared?!
Where's that usual stuck
up attitude you have?!
Well, now, this has certainly
turned into a problem.
Next Episode  "The Sword Devil, Shā Wú Shēng"
If fate leads people to meet, then
fate can also lead people to battle.
And sometimes, a lifelong
enemy can be met in passing.