Episode 7  "Demon Spine Mountains"
Master!
I suppose this could be
called a twist of fate.
Tiān Hái!
Miè Tiān Hái? That's him?
Yes. He's called the Bones of Creation,
and is the leader of the Xuán Guǐ Zōng.
Dān Fěi of the Duàn
Jiàn Cí... We meet again.
I had intended on leaving no
stone unturned in finding you,
so I'm grateful that you've
saved me the effort.
To think I could ambush you
so easily... Ridiculous.
It would've made far more
sense to simply take the
Tiān Xing Jiàn's guard and
run to the ends of the earth.
Do not insult me!
Do you think
the Hù Yìn Shī
would fear filth like you?!
Well, actually,
I did anticipate your foolish pride
luring you to my Seven Sins Tower.
Vengeance for your brother,
and the retrieval of the sword's handle...
Reckless! Foolhardy!
The very height of folly!
I am not alone.
With my six comrades,
I swear to bring retribution upon you!
Comrades? This lot?
The One-Eyed Impaler,
Xíng Hài the Night's Lament,
and even the Screaming Phoenix Killer
stand at your side, you say?
Are you really so ignorant
that you don't realize
who would assemble such a group?
Interesting.
You have my attention.
I will amuse myself
with this comical display for a bit longer.
Let us see how far your so-called comrades
manage to make it!
So he just ran?
No, I'd say it's more like he let us go.
These are the Demon Spine Mountains.
I see. This geography isn't ordinarily
seen in the world of man.
It makes me nostalgic for the demon realm.
I guess it's time to get down to business.
Well, I'd love to be optimistic
enough to say we're fully prepared,
but you should all remain cautious.
Death awaits the slightest
misstep from here on out.
No sense in worrying about it now.
Let's rest for tonight here.
In the morning, we can
check out these three obstacles.
Hey, up late practicing?
Since we enter the Demon Spine Mountains
tomorrow, I've been unable to sleep!
Hey, look.
Maybe this is none of my business, but...
aren't you kinda overdoing it?
What exactly do you think you understand?
Yeah, it's true that I don't get
this Hù Yìn Shī duty stuff,
or understand what exactly this Tiān
Xing Jiàn sword is supposed to be.
If I'm being real, most of what I understand
boils down to fighting techniques.
But even for someone like me, it seems
like you're pushing yourself way too hard.
What makes you say that?
Well, for instance, during
that set of moves...
When you do the big sweep
and stab three times.
Those are forms 12 through 15
of the 76 Dān Blade Techniques.
What of them?
I'm thinking you use the sweep
to put your foe off balance,
and the three stabs are
meant to be killing blows.
That's how it's supposed to work, right?
Uh... yes.
Well, in that case, it's kind of weird.
When you use the sweep,
they're forced back a step,
so they're out of range
for those three stabs.
Unless you step in and attack with that
momentum, I kinda don't see the point.
You're saying there are faults with
my clan's Dān Blade Techniques?
I get the feeling they were developed
with a man's build in mind.
In that case, it'd make sense.
With the length of a man's arms,
three stabs from that distance would land.
But...
If you wanna use this stuff in actual combat,
I'm guessing these are the three
forms, starting with number 13?
You gotta step forward while doing them.
A girl your size doesn't have the
kind of reach you need, otherwise.
With that kind of change to the footwork,
it disrupts the entire
sequence of techniques!
But isn't it useless anyway,
if it won't work in combat?
The traditions of my clan
carry more weight than my own life.
With my brother gone,
there is no one to pass on
the Dān Blade Techniques...
But me, alas.
Well, if you're the only one left,
don't you have to survive long enough
to pass those sword moves
to the next generation?
Which is why right now,
what you need to master is sword
fighting that'll keep you alive.
Not a sword that belongs
to your family's tradition,
but a sword that's yours and yours alone.
Are you implying
that I cannot wield the true
techniques because I am a woman?
That this training is a waste?
Nah, I didn't say it was a waste.
It'll probably be important to
teach the son you have, some day.
Wh-Wha...
Why are you suggesting
how I rear my children?!
What are you thinking?!
Uh, I was just...
How incredibly rude!
This is why I hate the brutish
men of the common world!
H-Hey!
Man, how do I always manage to make
girls mad when I talk to them?
I don't get it. Talk about complicated...
This air is crazy. Breathing it makes
me feel like my lungs are gonna rot.
This mist is noxious. Stay on your guard.
The effects are most likely slow-acting.
Wait. Something's nearby.
I see. This is the Valley of the Dead.
We've arrived at the first trial, then.
You say "arrived," but it looks like
we're already in the thick of it.
The time has come, Xíng Hài.
Yes, I know.
You, Hù Yìn Shī. You know how to erect
a field to repel the dark arts, right?
Of course. It's a simple matter.
I'll be vulnerable while singing.
You should ensure the dead cannot
reach me if the unexpected happens.
Understood. Could two of you hold this sash?
Once I create the field,
surround Lady Xíng Hài
with your blades piercing the ground.
You got it.
Right.
Hey, they've noticed us!
Now, you unfortunate souls...
Forget your dreams of hunger,
and turn to eternal rest!
Hey, is it working?
Huh?
Uh, what?
This isn't good!
Pixiu Holy Ward!
H-Hey, stupid! Why are you out there?!
What do you mean, "why"?!
Hey, what did you guys just do?! Seriously?
It was somewhat cramped in here.
I imagine six people fills it to capacity.
Hang on! Aren't they all
supposed to be put to sleep?!
Actually, what era are the dead here from?
How the hell would we know?!
Dead of a certain vintage
need memories of their
life to inform the song.
There's a subtle pitch shift in the song
that depends on when they died.
With their clothes in such shoddy shape,
it's impossible to tell.
I suppose there's no other way but
to try a variety of pitches then.
You really wanna improvise now?!
Yún Xiāo! Cán Yún!
Are you jerks seriously
gonna make me fight alone?!
Miss Dān Fěi, is it okay
if we let go of the sash?!
You can't! Sir Shāng, please, be patient!
You heard her. Don't take it personally.
Hey, Wú Shēng!
Where do you get off sitting down and
relaxing?! Get out here and fight!
My duty is to play the flute at the end.
I don't care to do much else.
Guǐ Niǎo?!
Would you pipe down? We're busy, over here.
That's not it.
I believe the tempo's too fast now.
Try a more gentle tune.
Like this?
Dammit, people! Stop screwing around!
This isn't a game!
It's not that, either. Not enough emotion.
It needs to be more like... hmm...
Please stop being silly and hurry!
I think I've almost got it...
Come on, Guǐ Niǎo!
Well done!
That settles it. They died 200 years ago.
The same time as the War
of Fading Dusk, it seems.
It's a sad story, if you
stop and consider it.
The sorcery of the Demon Spine Mountains
has left them bound
to this place for so long,
wandering and bloodthirsty.
And now they finally have peace.
We can at least pray for their souls.
You bastards... Was that on purpose?
Uh... Sir Shāng, are you all right?
Do I look all right?
I'm afraid we've wasted too
much time. Let's hurry on.
It's a bad idea to spend too
long in this noxious fog.
I believe the next obstacle is
the Valley of the Doll, yes?
The stone doll is supposed
to stand five jo tall.
It should be easy enough to
tell when we're getting closer.
I believe we're already here, then.
That's even bigger than I thought!
There'd be nothing left if
that thing stepped on you.
Isn't the weakness on the nape of it's neck?
I'm not seeing anything that seems obvious.
It may be on the other side.
It might not be visible from this angle.
If we get any closer, it'll start
moving. That'd be pointless.
Well, sitting around thinking
about it won't help.
We just need to get the statue
to turn the other way, right?
Do you have a proposal?
Well, we know how the device is set,
so let's get it to move for us.
Hey, come and get me! I'm over here!
Crap, it actually does move!
I see it! That's the weakness, right?!
A sorcerous charm.
Shatter that and it'll be nothing
more than a pile of stones.
Sir Shòu, take aim quickly!
I've got it.
He missed?
He missed.
What am I supposed to do now?!
Y'know, the stone doll has turned
our way, but it isn't attacking us.
It's most likely a particular mechanism...
Oh, I see!
Oh, most chivalrous and
gallant Sir Shāng Bù Huàn,
please listen to me and remain calm.
The puppet seems to only recognize
those who are in motion as threats.
Which means, while it has its sights on you,
as long as we remain here, we'll be safe.
That being the case, could you please
avoid getting too close to us?
Make sure when you run, you do it
in the opposite direction, okay?
Oh, damn it all!
Sir Shòu! Please, prepare
fire your next shot!
You say that,
but hitting such a tiny target, in motion,
at this distance, is no a simple matter.
That was a close one.
You can't blame him.
Having an off day occasionally is only human.
Hey, wait a second.
You're not human, though!
Are you guys screwing with me?!
You overgrown—!
No!
Well done!
As expected of the One-Eyed Impaler.
He doesn't miss when it counts the most.
Flattery's not gonna get you anywhere.
Uh... Sir Shāng, are you all right?
It's on purpose... I am positive
you guys are doing this on purpose!
Come now, is that any attitude
to take toward your savior?
That's right! If not for my bro's bow,
you would've been splattered!
That was easier than I had imagined.
Yeah. Kind of underwhelming for such
supposedly otherworldly threats.
This Labyrinth of Darkness
might be easier than expected, too.
Most likely.
After all, you must merely
play a flute to gain safe passage.
That's only if you don't slip up
during your playing, Wú Shēng.
Surely you jest.
This is it.
Come now, what's wrong, Bù Huàn?
You must be joking. This is as
far as I go with you people!
Next Time  "The Enigmatic Gale"
Divine retribution for evil.
Just deserts for past actions.
That is the nature of righteous judgment.
But when the journey comes to its end,
who will be writing its story?