Thunder. Lightning.
Our story begins with that which
shakes the heavens and earth.
Like a thunderbolt in a blue sky,
a startling fantasy begins to unfold!
Run! Dān Fěi, run!
Brother!
After them! Don't let them escape!
Foolish little girl...
Know now the price
of opposing the Xuán Guǐ Zōng!
I won't let you!
To think that your ancient
Hù Yìn Shī blade is so weak...
You make me laugh!
You underestimate the techniques
of the Dān, you cur?
Dān Blade Technique:
Flying Red Cloud Rush!
So you've dodged it. But...
There will not be a next time!
Precisely...
There will not be a next time.
All life is a prelude to death.
To serve me until you are a corpse,
or to be cut down and become one.
Your have two options at the end of my sword.
Sēn Luó Kū Gǔ...
Miè Tiān Hái!
What madness brought you
to our sacred ground?!
I have already told you what I'm after.
Now, give it to me.
I know that you two always have it with you,
and never let it out of your sight.
We'd never hand it over
to a villain like you!
Handing it over while you still live,
or prying it from your corpses...
That makes very little difference to me.
But I'm sure the difference
is much greater to you!
My duty carries more weight
than my own life...
If I fail in it, then there's no difference
between life and death!
Fool! I warned you
there would not be a next time!
Then face this!
Dān Blade Technique: Yang Sunrise!
Demonic War Force: Total Annihilation!
Brother!
Dān Fěi... you need to leave me and run...
Brother, I couldn't!
If even one of us siblings survives,
the Tiān Xing Jiàn sword will be protected!
Go!
You won't escape.
Go, Dān Fěi!
Brother!
Damn them!
Is that...?
That girl should have the guard
that belongs to this handle.
Find her, and leave no stone unturned.
I will be returning to Seven Sins Tower.
Yes, sir!
Find the girl!
Search everywhere downstream!
Episode 1  "Code of Umbrellas"
A truly wondrous journey does not require
horses to carry you over great distances,
or a luxurious carriage,
but enough time to stop and
aimlessly enjoy yourself.
One man, fully aware of this,
sits under a tree to stay out
of the rain, in no hurry at all.
Near him is a Buddha statue
with a broken roof...
But the statue is shielded from the rain
by an umbrella someone has left.
But who left this umbrella,
and under what conditions?
Damn it...
If I'm getting this wet,
I might as well be swimming through a river!
Well, it's my lucky day!
Hey, you there. Traveler.
You don't plan to steal
that umbrella, do you?
What? Is this your umbrella?
No, but it appears that someone took pity
on that Buddha statue and left it there.
That makes it an offering.
If the statue were clay or wood, sure,
but a stone statue will suffer no harm
by getting wet in the rain.
I, on the other hand, will catch a cold.
If you don't like the rain,
come sit under this tree.
I don't know how much time you have
on your hands, but I'm in a hurry.
It appears that you care
very little for the divine,
but I'm sure even a ruffian like you
has some sense of virtue.
Are you prepared to repay your debt?
My debt?
Yes. You just borrowed an umbrella
from that Buddha statue.
You don't plan to skip out on this, do you?
What are you trying to say?
In your travels,
no matter who it may be,
show the first person you see
some compassion, in place of the Buddha.
If you swear to do that,
I will bother you no more.
Man, you're annoying. All right, fine.
I'll show some compassion or whatever.
Remember, no matter what.
What a strange guy.
What the hell was that? Me showing
compassion in Buddha's place?
Do I look the type to do that?
The way she's walking...
Does she have some internal injuries?
Hey, you there.
You having some kind of trouble?
Yeah, all right. None of my business, I guess.
Huh?
We've got you now, little girl! Surrender!
What the hell do you guys want?
Hello?
How about before you go swinging
those nasty things around,
you tell me why you're doing that?
Why are you chasing her?
This has nothing to do with you.
If you interfere, you'll get hurt!
Well, you see...
There's a Buddha back there
that's getting drenched in this rain,
so I've got to save that girl.
What are you talking about?
Don't ask me! Well, anyway,
that's just how this goes.
You fool! You dare get in our way,
knowing we're the Xuán Guǐ Zōng?
Huh?
Do they call guys who chase around girls
the Xuán Guǐ Zōng around here?
What?!
Whoa, there.
Don't get angry.
I'm not from around here.
So I'm not very aware of
what goes on around here.
But...
Since you're all getting
mad with no explanation,
that must mean that you guys
don't care much for reason or logic.
Enough! Kill him!
Oh, damn it!
Retreat!
Hey! At least pay for my damn umbrella!
Damn it...
She's not hurt too badly.
This should do...
There.
Now, to let her rest somewhere...
Well, what do we have here?
I'm surprised you actually
helped someone because
of a debt owed to a Buddha statue.
It seems that true heroism is
something that belies appearances.
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
Are you mocking me or something?
So, what happened to that girl?
She doesn't seem the type
to be found collapsed on the road.
A bunch of thugs were
chasing her down in a group.
I think they called themselves
the Xuán Guǐ Zōng?
Xuán Guǐ Zōng?
You started a fight with the
Xuán Guǐ Zōng just to save a stranger?
What? Are they a big deal around here?
I thought you had a strange accent...
You're not from this country, are you?
I'd guess you've seen quite the long journey.
That's right.
Well, I'm taking off.
Wait. What about this girl?
I treated her wounds.
She'll wake up if she can
just rest here for a bit.
She might want to know her savior's name...
Just tell her it was the providence
of that wet Buddha over there.
Not only a man of little faith,
but little sentimentality...
Can you even imagine what kind of trouble
this young girl is going through?
You're telling me you can?
You understand the situation
someone you've never talked to is in?
Consider... the type of clothes she's in.
They belong to those who oversee the
Shén Huì Xiè Mó of the Qióng Mù Zhī Zhàn.
The clothes of a Hù Yìn Shī.
You sure you're not mistaken?
Why would a girl of such high standing
be wandering the night, alone?
Exactly.
The Hù Yìn Shī clans are not meant
to step outside sacred ground,
as they are tasked with
dedicating their lives to guard
the wisdom of the gods and
the tools of the demons.
Yet we have a bizarre story where one has
been attacked by a band of violent thugs...
This is something truly unusual.
Yeah, sounds bizarre.
So bizarre, so weird, that it stinks
of being a huge pain in the ass.
Which means I'm even less
interested in getting involved.
Even if you know this is a trial that is
too much for one wounded girl to handle?
Oh, shut up!
You've been sitting there
like this is my problem
with that smug look,
running your mouth,
but what are you gonna do about it?
If you wanna talk down to people
about showing mercy and whatnot,
then don't turn to others: you save the girl!
She already has a passionately
chivalrous defender in you.
No need for me to get involved.
You bastard...
I've got you now.
Did you really think you could escape?
See what I was talking about?
This girl's troubles aren't over yet.
You there!
I hear you got involved in this
out of some strange whim,
but if you hand over the girl peacefully,
I'll turn a blind eye to your
mistake, just this once.
The truly wise know well enough
to avoid trouble, you know.
An excellent proverb, perhaps,
but no amount of wisdom can protect you
from every misfortune, at all times.
What?!
You bastard—!
The girl?! When did she—?!
Whoa, what the hell's gotten into you?!
You won't escape this time!
Hand over the Tiān Xing Jiàn's guard!
Or prepare to die!
What are you talking about?
Have you gone nuts?
You bastard, you played some
kind of trick, didn't you?!
Well now, I'm not sure what you mean.
And no matter how wise a man may be,
some troubles he must deal with directly.
Son of a bitch!
Would you snap out of it already?!
Damn you... Damn you!
Look, you wanna just drop this?
You and I have no reason to die
or kill amongst ourselves.
Never! That can never happen!
The shame of this these wounds
can only be soothed with your blood!
Oh, yeah?
You care more about that than your life, huh?
Understood. No need for you
to feel shame anymore.
Because I'm gonna get serious now!
Dry Bones, Blood Slash!
Formless Rogue Sword: Eight-Way Arrival!
I can't die... I can't die like this...!
I've dedicated my life to the sword...
I can't die without knowing the name
of the man who struck me down!
My name is Shāng Bù Huàn.
If you're satisfied with that,
go ahead and pass on.
Shāng Bù Huàn... Shāng Bù Huàn!
I have your name...
The name of our enemy, who incurred
the wrath of the Xuán Guǐ Zōng!
Wha—
Shāng Bù Huàn... There will be
no refuge for you now...
The soldiers of the Xuán Guǐ Zōng
will chase you to the ends of the earth!
Whoa, whoa, what was all that?
It seems you've taken a
greater burden onto yourself.
This is what it means to make
a foe of the Xuán Guǐ Zōng.
Dammit, you bastard, if you hadn't—
Where am I...?
A Cui Huī Jiàn sword
of the Hù Yìn Shī...
And one made for a woman's use.
I believe this belongs to you, am I correct?
Who are you two?
Uh... well...
Between the world of man
and the world of devils,
the natural barrier, Mó Jǐ Shān.
The Seven Sins Tower that
stands at its highest point
is the headquarters of the cruel
and villainous Xuán Guǐ Zōng.
What's become of Cán Xiōng and his men?
Sire.
There's been no new word from them.
I-Is that—?!
Well, Cán Xiōng...
You've returned looking
all the more manly for your efforts.
Who could've done this?
Who, indeed?
Why not find out from the man himself?
Lüè Fēng Qiè Chén, eh?
How amusing to find him standing in our way!
Next Time "Attack of the Xuán Guǐ Zōng!"
An ancient, stolen treasure.
The tears of a maiden for her late brother.
A wise man teaches to avoid danger,
but rising to a challenge is a man's path.