Episode 3: The Woman In Night Devil Forest
I ask you again: are you Shāng Bù Huàn?
And what if I am?
Hey, bro! Good work out there.
I wouldn't have bothered if you
had handled things yourself, Juǎn.
Aw, you've got me there!
But since our friend here is in one piece...
Hey, how about someone explain
what the hell's going on?
Why are you guys fighting the
Xuán Guǐ Zōng on my behalf?
I received a message from an acquaintance.
"If you encounter Shāng Bù Huàn,
help him out," he asked.
What kind of friend is this guy
if you'll fight to the
death at his request?
Why, it's me, of course.
Does anyone else come to mind?
We meet again. What are
you calling yourself now?
If you could, go with Guǐ Niǎo for now.
Understood.
And you'll be in charge, as usual.
Thank you.
I must ask, who's this young fellow?
He's been helping me out lately.
His name is Juǎn Cán Yún.
I thought he might be of some use,
so I brought him along.
Hey there!
If my bro Shòu here takes orders
from you, then count me in, too.
Good to be working with you!
I am a Hù Yìn Shī guardian
of the Duàn Jiàn Cí shrine,
my name is Dān Fěi.
It's a pleasure to meet you both.
Whoa... she's so beautiful!
A celestial maiden?
Whoa, hang on! Just hang on a second!
Quit trying to move this
conversation along without me!
I'm sure you've realized now how
the Xuán Guǐ Zōng operate.
They're not a pleasant bunch you can
avoid by simply running from them.
Yeah...
I guess I've just gotta take down their
leader, this Miè Tiān Hái, right?
That'll turn these guys who are just
his lapdogs into a unorganized mob.
And do you know where
where Miè Tiān Hái is?
We are about to head to the
domain of the Xuán Guǐ Zōng,
Seven Sins Tower in the
Demon Spine Mountains.
Our enemies, many.
Meaning the more allies we have, the better.
If our goals are aligned, there's
no reason for us not to be allied.
I don't care what your goal is!
And this can be settled if I head
to this Seven Sins Tower on my own.
No matter what, I'm not
working with you! See ya!
Oh, proud, obstinate Sir Shāng Bù Huàn...
I hate to break this to you, but...
What now?
The Demon Spine Mountains
are in that direction.
Don't try following me, got it?!
Uh, sir, our business is in
the same direction, so...
Funny confidence, isn't it?
Looks like we're on the same road for now.
We don't mind you tagging along, though.
Do whatever you want!
The Demon Spine Mountains, where Seven
Sins Tower stands, is at the border
of the human and demon realms.
It is a land that can be said
to be part of the afterlife.
People in the area don't even
risk looking in its direction,
much less traveling there.
Sounds like a weird place
to set up an organization.
Seven Sins Tower was originally
the study of a powerful sorcerer.
Miè Tiān Hái was once a simple
guard there when he was young,
but in the master's absence, he has made
the abandoned tower his personal property.
What are the odds this master ended
up dying at Miè's hands himself?
A very likely theory.
Miè didn't just take the tower,
but also the knowledge
of several spells his master knew,
and made them his own.
For instance, the ability to drain
memories from the heads of the dead.
I guess that's why they knew
my name and what I looked like.
The real problem is that
the barrier the sorcerer erected to
protect the mountain is still intact.
The only real way to its summit is
guarded by three extraordinary obstacles
which ensure that no ordinary
people could ever reach it.
How are the Xuán Guǐ Zōng
getting in and out of it, then?
Through the air.
You saw the flying beasts
they were using, right?
They are the only way to move freely
to and from Seven Sins Tower.
I guess if you have to fly to get in,
that's about as secure as it gets.
Then what are we supposed to do?
You expect us to grow wings,
like those beasts?
We use extraordinary methods
to make our way along
the ground past the extraordinary obstacles.
It's our only path to victory.
Come on, seriously?
As I explained, there are three obstacles
preventing access to the summit.
The first is the Valley of the Dead.
Corpses whose souls are chained
to their bodies in death
roam the area in mobs.
They hunger for the flesh
and blood of the living.
Being found by them will
result in being torn apart.
What do we do, then?
There is a special requiem for the
dead that a necromancer can perform,
which will stop corpses from moving,
putting them to rest.
So in order to cross this valley, we need
to add a necromancer to our number.
Necromancy...
Must we truly rely on such dreadful methods?
I can understand your distaste,
as a Hù Yìn Shī.
But we are trying to enter an evil place,
where ordinary means will not suffice.
We have no choice but to
follow the laws of the land.
But do you have anyone in mind?
Let's just say that it
shouldn't be a concern.
In the meantime, we'll continue
discussing the Demon Spine Mountains.
The second obstacle is
the Valley of the Doll.
A castle-sized, animated stone
doll serves as its guardian.
It ordinarily looks like a statue,
but when it detects trespassers,
it begins to move,
attempting to crush them mercilessly.
Someone valued their security too damn much.
Thankfully, it's little more
than an elaborate trap.
If it were a true giant, there'd
be little we could do...
But if it's being animated mechanically,
then its power must have a source.
So we've gotta smash its power source.
But how easy will it be for us to get to it?
It's in the nape of the
stone guardian's neck.
Not a height one could easily reach,
even when stretching...
What do we do, then?
It is a height that the Sharp-Eyed
Impaler might land an arrow upon, though.
In other words...
If an arrow can reach it, then I can hit it.
Which explains my invitation on this quest.
Precisely.
You are our key to passing
this second obstacle.
That leaves the third and final obstacle.
It is known as the Labyrinth of Darkness.
With the exception of the actual exit,
it has countless paths that lead
to separate, warped dimensions.
Meaning that stepping off
the correct path, even once,
will leave you trapped for eternity,
before you even realize it.
That sounds even more
hopeless than the other two!
Fight magic with magic, my friend.
An acquaintance of mine has a treasure
known as the Soul Echo Flute.
By following the echo
of the sound it produces,
this magic flute will always
lead you in the right direction.
We'll be asking for
his help with this obstacle.
And in every single case, you're counting
on someone else to solve the problem.
You never do anything yourself, do you?
It takes an appreciation for
someone's abilities to know
which tasks suit them best.
I'd rather you compliment my
wealth of wonderful friends.
You've certainly got that.
The owner of the Soul Echo Flute
is far away at the moment,
so it will be a while until
they receive my message.
The necromancer who can use the
requiem is in the local area, but...
There's been no response yet.
They're probably just
sick of dealing with you.
That would be a problem...
It would be for the best to have her help in
passing through the Valley of the Dead.
If she won't answer, we'll have
to go to her and convince her.
Her? It's a woman?
Hold on! And you said she lives nearby.
You're not talking about
Night Devil Forest, are you?
Yes. She's been cooped up in
that forest for a long time.
She's never been very sociable, after all.
You're talking about Xíng Hài?
You intend to add Xíng Hài,
the Night's Lament, to this group?
That sounds like crazy talk!
Wait...
You two know this Xíng Hài lady?
What is she like?
Well, she's not the most
socially well-adjusted woman,
so she tends to invite misunderstandings.
No, no, no! This goes way
beyond misunderstandings!
Surely we can find someone
else with the spiritual power
to silence the dead elsewhere,
if we look for them!
Why in the world would we ask Xíng Hài?
Because she's the best at it.
Much like how the Sharp-Eyed
Impaler's archery is the best.
These objectives needs to be handled by
the best of their respective fields.
After all, we face the Bones of Creation.
We need a number of people who
are as prepared as possible.
I guess when you put it that way...
Just for the record, I warned you!
It's open.
What brings you by this late?
I thought that if I offered
a reasonable explanation,
you might understand why we
must do this, Sir Shāng.
And the importance of the Tiān Xing Jiàn...
This again?
Could it be that...
You don't believe how fearsome it is?
And that we Hù Yìn Shī
protect its resting place
is a mere superstition?
I've traveled all over, y'know.
I've heard rumors about mystic
weapons plenty of times before.
And I've had plenty of people
tell me, "This is the real thing!"
Like they're trying to show off.
And most of the time, they're fakes.
They hold up a piece of junk like a
treasure, trying to feel important.
It's true that that when
dealing with mystic weapons,
there are many imitations...
But there is only one Tiān Xing Jiàn.
Have you ever checked it out personally?
Has anyone taken it up and swung it around?
Well...
When the Xuán Guǐ Zōng came after it,
you Hù Yìn Shī should've
done exactly that.
If the Tiān Xing Jiàn was just junk,
Miè Tiān Hái would've had to
have laughed and turned away.
And if it was the real deal,
you could've used it to mete out some
divine punishment on the bastard.
That sounds like a fair use of a
sword made for fighting evil, right?
But to do something so dreadful...
No matter how mystic or remarkable
a sword is, it's still a sword.
It's just a tool. Not a god.
How can you be afraid of using
it without even touching it first?
Among my clan, that's the gravest taboo!
You're saying that's what
we should have done?
Sounds to me like what
you're really afraid of...
Is breaking with the tradition
that your ancestors established.
That can't be...
I feel bad for your brother.
But this thing doesn't sound like
it's worse losing your life over,
and definitely not worth risking
your life to clean up the mess it caused.
But... we've...
We're leaving early tomorrow, right?
Quit wasting time around
here and get some rest.
This might be our last chance
to sleep somewhere decent.
Right...
Now, then...
Peeping, huh? That's a real
noble hobby you've got.
Hey, don't make it sound so terrible!
I-I was just trying to make sure you
didn't try anything with Miss Dān Fěi!
Now who's making insulting assumptions?
Well, you were picking on her, weren't you?
She looked really sad just now!
Quit trying to paint me as the bad
guy if you don't know what happened.
Like I was asking, what happened?!
Neither my bro or Mister
Guǐ Niǎo will explain!
Why's Miss Dān Fěi so desperate?!
You just tagged along as the
bow master's sidekick, anyway.
You don't need to know.
Ow, ow, ow!
I'm not just gonna drop it!
I can't talk to Miss Dān Fěi about
it unless I know what's going on!
So that's what you're after.
I mean, she's so pretty, right?
And acts so cute...
Look, just give it a rest.
She belongs to a prim and
proper Hù Yìn Shī family.
There's no way she'd be a good
match for a goof like you.
Nope! If I let this slip by...
I mean, a chance to get close to someone
with as high a standing as a Hù Yìn Shī...
It might never come again, y'know?
In that case, I need to work as hard
as I can to make the best of it!
Quit being stupid and go to bed.
H-Hey!
Maybe if I was more famous...
So that when they hear
"The Frozen Wonder of the Spear,"
any girl would sigh in awe...
I'm not there yet.
Excuse me, but... does someone
actually live in this place?
The air in this forest is strange, somehow.
Someone unprepared would go
crazy from being here too long.
That's exactly what I'd expect
from Xíng Hài's domain.
She'd never have the same domestic
preferences that a human would.
Wait... what do you mean by that?
You fools who have entered
the Night Devil Forest...
Have you trespassed on this ground
knowing it to be the home of Xíng Hài ?
Don't panic. It's just an illusion.
Think of it as the nameplate
hanging on her door.
If you leave immediately,
very well. If not...
You will experience otherworldly suffering
before losing your life!
This is your final warning!
Wh-What was that?
Her idea of greeting visitors.
A bit of a roundabout way to put it, I know.
Do your ears work right?
And that was Xíng Hài? She looked
like some kind of evil demon!
I said she was a woman,
but I never said she was human.
You want to invite a demon
to join us? Are you insane?!
You can say the word "demon"...
But there were those who did
not return to the demon realm
after the War of Fading Dusk
because they had some attachment
to the human realm.
It's prejudiced of you to
assume that they're all bad.
Some of them are quite good-natured.
It's true that not all demons
are necessarily evil.
But they say...
Xíng Hài makes youth elixirs from
the freshly-butchered livers of children.
She's as evil as demons come.
Yeah, she's the one who wanted
to make an ideal living doll,
so she cut up 100 beautiful men
to collect the parts, isn't she?
Those are just rumors. Have you two
actually seen her do anything evil before?
But even then, if she's a demon
that practices necromancy...
That means she's steeped in the darkest arts.
If they can understand our words,
and are capable of understanding
simple cost and benefit...
They can be negotiated into
cooperating, no matter who they are.
We just need to present the right offer.
And maybe she didn't respond to your summons
because she didn't like your offer?
Which necessitates talking to her directly.
Her help is absolutely necessary
for our endeavor, after all.
You still wanna do this?
After getting such a clear
"no visitors" message?
I already told you,
what we saw was an illusion.
It would've shown the same,
no matter who came through,
saying the same things, before disappearing.
It's no different than having a sign posted.
But the sign said something along
the lines of, "Enter and die!"
I must meet Xíng Hài
herself to discuss this.
And standing here discussing matters
won't help move things along.
Now, let's go!
So... now that we've ignored her little
warning and decided to trespass...
What are we gonna be dealing with?
Most likely we'll have to deal with
the barking of her guard dogs.
Guard dogs?! Are they who
you're talking about?
Well, what sense would it make for
a necromancer to keep live dogs?
I am really starting to want to sew
that smug mouth of yours shut.
You're certain you know how
to convince this demon?
Of course.
Then I shall occupy these pitiful corpses.
Use that chance to move on, Sir Guǐ Niǎo.
Hey! That's dangerous!
Leaving a girl alone to hold this spot...
Juǎn, you stay behind and assist
our honorable Hù Yìn Shī.
Oh, you got it!
Tornado Clearing!
Huh, looks like you can back
up some of that big mouth.
I wouldn't have brought him if I
didn't think he'd come in handy.
Come on, let's move.
You two, remember, you need
only buy us some time.
Do not overextend yourselves.
Understood.
Come on, come on, come on!
It's finally time for me to strut my stuff!
You can get back, Miss Dān Fěi!
I can handle them alone!
Oh, no, don't mind me.
Dān Blade Technique:
Flowering Night Judgment!
S-So elegant!
To falter in the face of dark arts
would bring shame on the Hù Yìn Shī.
Now, attack me as you will!
Dragon Storm Strike!
Dān Blade Technique: Sacred Bristle Ward!
We make quite the pair, don't we?
Please stop being silly
and focus on the battle.
Damn you... damn you,  Enigmatic Gale!
You ignore my warning and disrupt
my refuge in these woods?!
You will pay...
I swear that you will pay for this!
A dream lasts a single night.
Love, a single summer.
Next Time  "The Whereabouts of the Soul Echo Flute"
Hatred... a lifetime.
The comeuppance for past deeds bares it's
fangs with no consideration for the moment.